PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Hoeber, Stefanie; Leuschner, Christoph; Koehler, Lars; Arias-Aguilar, Dagoberto; Schuldt, Bernhard								The importance of hydraulic conductivity and wood density to growth performance in eight tree species from a tropical semi-dry climate								FOREST ECOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT				330				126	136		10.1016/j.foreco.2014.06.039			OCT 15 2014	2014	Understanding how tropical trees coordinate fast growth with water consumption and carbon investment is of high relevance because climate warming may expose tropical forests to increasing stress. Thus, foresters require more information of native tree species envisaged for reforestation. This study examines the relationship between productivity and possibly growth-determining functional traits of xylem anatomy, hydraulic conductivity, foliar morphology and nutrient status in eight tree species in semi-dry Costa Rica; we further assessed the indicative value of wood density for growth rate and hydraulic efficiency. We tested the hypotheses that (i) wood density is related to both growth rate and hydraulic efficiency contrary to findings from moist tropical forests, and (ii) productivity is closely related to branch xylem properties as well as empirically determined hydraulic conductivity in these drought-adapted species. Growth rate was positively related to tree size, foliar nitrogen content, vessel diameter, specific conductivity and leaf water potential, and negatively to vessel density, wood density and delta C-13, indicating that fast-growing tree species with light wood possessed a more efficient hydraulic system but closed their stomata relatively early to prevent xylem dysfunction. We conclude, that in tropical semi-dry climates, productivity is closely associated not only with foliar nitrogen but also with wood anatomical and hydraulic properties. Wood density proved to be a reliable indicator for growth-related, wood anatomical and hydraulic traits in these drought-adapted species. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									0	0	0	0	0	0378-1127		WOS:000342244500014		J	Hajek, Peter; Leuschner, Christoph; Hertel, Dietrich; Delzon, Sylvain; Schuldt, Bernhard								Trade-offs between xylem hydraulic properties, wood anatomy and yield in Populus.								Tree physiology				34	7			744	56		10.1093/treephys/tpu048			2014-Jul	2014	Trees face the dilemma that achieving high plant productivity is accompanied by a risk of drought-induced hydraulic failure due to a trade-off in the trees' vascular system between hydraulic efficiency and safety. By investigating the xylem anatomy of branches and coarse roots, and measuring branch axial hydraulic conductivity and vulnerability to cavitation in 4-year-old field-grown aspen plants of five demes (Populus tremula L. and Populus tremuloides Michx.) differing in growth rate, we tested the hypotheses that (i) demes differ in wood anatomical and hydraulic properties, (ii) hydraulic efficiency and safety are related to xylem anatomical traits, and (iii) aboveground productivity and hydraulic efficiency are negatively correlated to cavitation resistance. Significant deme differences existed in seven of the nine investigated branch-related anatomical and hydraulic traits but only in one of the four coarse-root-related anatomical traits; this likely is a consequence of high intra-plant variation in root morphology and the occurrence of a few 'high-conductivity roots'. Growth rate was positively related to branch hydraulic efficiency (xylem-specific conductivity) but not to cavitation resistance; this indicates that no marked trade-off exists between cavitation resistance and growth. Both branch hydraulic safety and hydraulic efficiency significantly depended on vessel size and were related to the genetic distance between the demes, while the xylem pressure causing 88% loss of hydraulic conductivity (P88 value) was more closely related to hydraulic efficiency than the commonly used P50 value. Deme-specific variation in the pit membrane structure may explain why vessel size was not directly linked to growth rate. We conclude that branch hydraulic efficiency is an important growth-influencing trait in aspen, while the assumed trade-off between productivity and hydraulic safety is weak.									0	0	0	0	0			MEDLINE:25009155	25009155	J	Dettmann, Sebastian; Perez, Cecilia A.; Thomas, Frank M.								Xylem anatomy and calculated hydraulic conductance of four Nothofagus species with contrasting distribution in South-Central Chile								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				27	3			685	696		10.1007/s00468-012-0824-2			JUN 2013	2013	Nothofagus obliqua, N. dombeyi, N. alpina and N. antarctica are characteristic tree species of the temperate forests on the western slopes of the Andes with centres of distribution that differ in their temperature and moisture regimes. We tested branch wood from co-occurring specimens of these species for the inherent differences in xylem anatomy and theoretical hydraulic conductance to evaluate their resistance to drought or frost. The hydraulic conductivity of the xylem was calculated using a modified Hagen-Poiseuille equation and related to wood density. Conduit dimensions were used to predict the water potential that would cause 50 % loss of hydraulic conductivity (I (50)). Nothofagus alpina, which mainly grows at sites with low frost frequency, exhibited the largest conduits and the highest mean values for conduit area, fraction of conduit area in the cross-section and hydraulic conductivity, but the lowest wood density. Opposite relationships were found in the plastic N. antarctica, whose xylem seems to be least vulnerable to freezing-induced, but also to drought-induced embolism. Calculated I (50) was highest (least negative) in N. alpina, indicating a relatively high susceptibility to cavitation. The xylem of the thermophilic N. obliqua and of N. dombeyi, which mainly occurs under oceanic climate, but can also survive at sporadically dry and warm sites, is not particularly adapted to periods of drought stress. Across all species, wood density was negatively correlated with the calculated hydraulic conductance. The xylem traits of N. alpina might contribute to its relatively high growth rate and facilitate its spread into forest gaps.									1	0	1	0	1	0931-1890		WOS:000319015800019		J	Lusk, Christopher H.; Kelly, Jeff W. G.; Gleason, Sean M.								Light requirements of Australian tropical vs. cool-temperate rainforest tree species show different relationships with seedling growth and functional traits								ANNALS OF BOTANY				111	3			479	488		10.1093/aob/mcs289			MAR 2013	2013	Background and Aims A trade-off between shade tolerance and growth in high light is thought to underlie the temporal dynamics of humid forests. On the other hand, it has been suggested that tree species sorting on temperature gradients involves a trade-off between growth rate and cold resistance. Little is known about how these two major trade-offs interact.Methods Seedlings of Australian tropical and cool-temperate rainforest trees were grown in glasshouse environments to compare growth versus shade-tolerance trade-offs in these two assemblages. Biomass distribution, photosynthetic capacity and vessel diameters were measured in order to examine the functional correlates of species differences in light requirements and growth rate. Species light requirements were assessed by field estimation of the light compensation point for stem growth.Results Light-demanding and shade-tolerant tropical species differed markedly in relative growth rates (RGR), but this trend was less evident among temperate species. This pattern was paralleled by biomass distribution data: specific leaf area (SLA) and leaf area ratio (LAR) of tropical species were significantly positively correlated with compensation points, but not those of cool-temperate species. The relatively slow growth and small SLA and LAR of Tasmanian light-demanders were associated with narrow vessels and low potential sapwood conductivity.Conclusions The conservative xylem traits, small LAR and modest RGR of Tasmanian light-demanders are consistent with selection for resistance to freeze-thaw embolism, at the expense of growth rate. Whereas competition for light favours rapid growth in light-demanding trees native to environments with warm, frost-free growing seasons, frost resistance may be an equally important determinant of the fitness of light-demanders in cool-temperate rainforest, as seedlings establishing in large openings are exposed to sub-zero temperatures that can occur throughout most of the year.									3	0	3	0	3	0305-7364		WOS:000316691800015	23264237	J	Martinez-Cabrera, Hugo I.; Estrada-Ruiz, Emilio; Castaneda-Posadas, Carlos; Woodcock, Deborah								Wood specific gravity estimation based on wood anatomical traits: Inference of key ecological characteristics in fossil assemblages								REVIEW OF PALAEOBOTANY AND PALYNOLOGY				187				1	10		10.1016/j.revpalbo.2012.08.005			NOV 1 2012	2012	Specific gravity (SG) is a key functional trait that has been linked to plant life history traits (e.g. growth rate, life spans) and ecological properties (e.g. cavitation resistance, water transport capacity). SG estimation can thus provide important information about the ecological characteristics of fossil assemblages. Since SG is also related to wood productivity, it can also inform about forest biomass and variation in terrestrial carbon stores over time. Here, we develop a straightforward method to predict SG based on wood anatomical traits that are frequently measured when fossil samples are described. We modeled the relationship of SG as a function of fiber and vessel traits in three extant Mexican communities (135 spp) and selected the best predictive equations. Fiber wall to lumen ratio was the variable most highly related with SG and was present in all the selected prediction models; this variable, together with vessel diameter, was part of the best model. In the validation datasets these models provided good estimates of SG both, at individual sample (overall R-2=0.63, varying from 0.44 to 0.84 in different localities) and average community levels. We applied these models to predict SG in three Mexican and one Peruvian fossil assemblages that ranged from Eocene to Miocene in age. To determine the reliability of the estimates, we compared them to observed SG from other extant communities and geographic regions. The estimates of two of the Mexican paleofloras were relatively high, most likely due to deficient preservation. In the other two fossil assemblages, El Cien Formation, Mexico and El Bosque Petrificado Piedra Chamana, Peru, the results were consistent with their inferred paleoenvironment and with the current understanding of the vegetation type they represented. The Peruvian paleoflora had relatively low SG suggesting comparatively higher growth rates and wood productivity, and relatively milder conditions compared to El Cien Formation paleoflora. (C) 2012 Elsevier By. All rights reserved.									0	0	0	0	0	0034-6667		WOS:000312520700001		J	Alameda, David; Villar, Rafael								Linking root traits to plant physiology and growth in Fraxinus angustifolia Vahl. seedlings under soil compaction conditions								ENVIRONMENTAL AND EXPERIMENTAL BOTANY				79				49	57		10.1016/j.envexpbot.2012.01.004			JUL 2012	2012	Roots are immersed in a soil matrix with different and contrasting conditions that may affect their anatomy, structure and function. Soil chemical factors, texture and compaction are some of the main factors experienced by roots. This study investigates how soil compaction and soil type can modify root anatomy and morphology, and, thus, plant physiology and growth. Seedlings of a woody species (Fraxinus angustifolia Vahl.) were grown in a greenhouse with two types of soil (loam and sandy-loam) under a wide range of soil compaction. Despite intrinsic differences in the chemical properties of the two soils, soil compaction explained much of the variation in root morphology and anatomy. We found, in a single species, a high root plasticity in different key root traits as a response to soil compaction. Soil compaction affected negatively the proportion of fine roots, specific root length and proportion of the root xylem vessels. These effects on root traits had an influence on plant physiology and growth. A causal model (by d-sep method) found that soil compaction affected specific root length, and this affects transpiration and photosynthesis rates. Also, the effect of soil compaction on xylem vessel proportion and xylem vessel diameter affected plant area and plain biomass. In conclusion, soil compaction shows an important effect on root anatomy and morphology during the seedling stage, with consequences on plant physiology and growth. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									5	0	5	0	5	0098-8472		WOS:000302592900007		J	Fan, Ze-Xin; Zhang, Shi-Bao; Hao, Guang-You; Slik, J. W. Ferry; Cao, Kun-Fang				Cao, Kun-Fang/D-2157-2009	Cao, Kun-Fang/0000-0002-0423-4985			Hydraulic conductivity traits predict growth rates and adult stature of 40 Asian tropical tree species better than wood density								JOURNAL OF ECOLOGY				100	3			732	741		10.1111/j.1365-2745.2011.01939.x			MAY 2012	2012	1. Stem xylem characteristics have a great impact on growth and adult stature of trees because of their role in mechanical support, long-distance water transport and whole-plant carbon allocation. Yet, despite the potential causal link between xylem traits and plant growth/adult stature, most studies have tried to link wood density, an indirect but easy to measure proxy for wood properties, to tree growth and size.2. To determine whether xylem traits outperform wood density as predictors of tree growth and stature, we evaluated the covariation among wood density, xylem anatomical traits, tree diameter growth rate and adult stature in 40 Asian tropical tree species through principal component analyses and through bivariate correlation, both across species and across phylogenetically independent contrasts.3. Vessel diameter exhibited a tight negative relationship with vessel frequency. Wood density showed a significant correlation with vessel diameter and density, but not with vessel fraction. Most correlations between functional traits indicate adaptive coordination, demonstrated by significant correlations between phylogenetically independent contrasts.4. Across species, diameter growth rate and adult stature were positively correlated with vessel lumen diameter and potential hydraulic conductivity, but not with wood density. Thus, our results suggest that xylem anatomical traits that are linked to hydraulic conductivity are better predictors of tree growth rate and adult stature than wood density.5. Synthesis. We found that xylem anatomical traits have a more significant influence on whole-plant performance due to their direct association with stem hydraulic conductivity, whereas wood density is decoupled from hydraulic function due to complex variations in xylem components.									17	3	19	1	21	0022-0477		WOS:000302623200015		J	Ishiguri, F.; Takeuchi, M.; Makino, K.; Wahyudi, I.; Takashima, Y.; Iizuka, K.; Yokota, S.; Yoshizawa, N.								CELL MORPHOLOGY AND WOOD PROPERTIES OF SHOREA ACUMINATISSIMA PLANTED IN INDONESIA								IAWA JOURNAL				33	1			25	38					2012	2012	In view of the importance of long-rotation plantation forestry in SE Asia to limit soil erosion, the cell morphology and wood properties of 35-year-old plantation trees of yellow meranti, Shorea acuminatissima Sym. were studied. To understand the effects of growth rate on cell morphology and wood properties, 131 trees in a stand were classified according to their stem diameter as fast-, medium-, and slow-growing. Five trees in each category were selected for determining the cell morphology and wood properties. There were significant differences in vessel diameter, vessel frequency, and cell wall thickness of wood fibers in the three categories. The fast-growing trees had a relatively low frequency of wide vessels and thick-walled wood fibers. However, no significant differences in basic density or compressive strength parallel to grain were identified in the three categories. The radial variation in the cell morphology and wood properties showed an almost identical pattern in the three categories, suggesting that xylem maturation depends on the cambial age rather than growth rate.									3	0	1	0	3	0928-1541		WOS:000302275500003		J	Bauerle, Taryn L.; Centinari, Michela; Bauerle, William L.								Shifts in xylem vessel diameter and embolisms in grafted apple trees of differing rootstock growth potential in response to drought								PLANTA				234	5			1045	1054		10.1007/s00425-011-1460-6			NOV 2011	2011	We investigated responses of plant growth rate, hydraulic resistance, and xylem cavitation in scion-rootstock-combinations of Malus domestica L. cv. Honeycrisp scions grafted onto a high-shoot vigor (HSV) rootstock, (semi-dwarfing Malling111), or onto a low-shoot vigor (LSV) rootstock, (dwarfing Budagovsky 9), in response to substrate moisture limitation. Adjustments in xylem vessel diameter and frequency were related to hydraulic resistance measurements for high- versus low- vigor apple trees. We observed a greater tolerance to water deficit in the high-shoot compared to the low-shoot vigor plants under water deficit as evidenced by increased growth in several plant organs, and greater scion anatomical response to limited water availability with ca. 25% increased vessel frequency and ca. 28% narrower current season xylem ring width. Whereas water limitation resulted in greater graft union hydraulic resistance of high-shoot vigor trees, the opposite was true when water was not limiting. The graft union of the low-shoot vigor rootstock exhibited higher hydraulic resistance under well-watered conditions. Scions of high-shoot vigor rootstocks had fewer embolisms at low plant water status compared to scions of low-shoot vigor rootstocks, presumably as a result of large differences in xylem vessel diameter. Our results demonstrated that anatomical differences were related to shifts in hydraulic conductivity and cavitation events, a direct result of grafting, under limited soil water.									6	2	6	0	8	0032-0935		WOS:000296378000014	21710199	J	Muramatsu, Noboru; Yamamoto, Masashi; Nakano, Hatsunori; Yamanouchi, Hiroaki								Analysis of factors governing water flow traits in fruiting plants twigs								SCIENTIA HORTICULTURAE				130	1			175	180		10.1016/j.scienta.2011.06.033			AUG 26 2011	2011	We compared hydraulic traits of 18 tropical/subtropical fruit-producing species plants and a further 18 from temperate zone. Plants were classified into four categories by height: tall tree (>10 m), small tree (4-9 m), shrub (1-4 m) and vine. We measured ratios [(cross-section area of xylem)/(cross-section area of twig)], and the diameters and numbers of xylem vessels in microscopic images. We calculated the water flow index (WFI: Sigma r(4) S(-1) x xylem ratio, where, r is the vessel radius, and 5 is the xylem cross-section area) according to Hagen-Poiseuille's law. Vine had thick vessels and remarkably higher WFI than freestanding trees in both temperate and tropical fruit species. Vessel diameter increased as trees being taller in both in latitudinal groups. Xylem vessel number decreased with height in temperate fruit trees but not in tropical species. WFI increased with tree height of both latitudinal groups. There were no significant effects of latitude on WFI. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									0	0	0	0	0	0304-4238		WOS:000294942900027		J	Ishiguri, Futoshi; Wahyudi, Imam; Takeuchi, Masae; Takashima, Yuya; Iizuka, Kazuya; Yokota, Shinso; Yoshizawa, Nobuo								Wood properties of Pericopsis mooniana grown in a plantation in Indonesia								JOURNAL OF WOOD SCIENCE				57	3			241	246		10.1007/s10086-010-1163-9			JUN 2011	2011	The relationships between growth characteristics and wood properties were investigated for a threatened species, Pericopsis mooniana, to promote the establishment of plantations of this species in the tropics. Growth characteristics (diameter and height) and stress-wave velocity (SWV) of trees were measured for 22-year-old P. mooniana trees planted in Indonesia. The trees were categorized into three groups, fast-growing, middle-growing, and slow-growing trees, to investigate the effect of growth rate on the wood properties. In addition, radial variation of anatomical characteristics and wood properties were determined. No significant correlation was found between growth characteristics and SWV. The values for the vessel diameter, cell wall thickness of wood fibers, wood fiber length, basic density, modulus of elasticity, and modulus of rupture from wood at the bark side were higher than those at the pith side. On the other hand, vessel frequency gradually decreased from pith to bark. These results suggested that low-quality wood, such as juvenile wood, existed near the pith area.									8	0	1	0	8	1435-0211		WOS:000291802000011		J	Russo, Sabrina E.; Jenkins, Kerry L.; Wiser, Susan K.; Uriarte, Maria; Duncan, Richard P.; Coomes, David A.				wiser, susan/G-1975-2011; Coomes, David/H-5630-2011; Duncan, Richard/E-7899-2013; Uriarte, Maria/L-8944-2013	Duncan, Richard/0000-0003-2295-449X; 			Interspecific relationships among growth, mortality and xylem traits of woody species from New Zealand								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				24	2			253	262		10.1111/j.1365-2435.2009.01670.x			APR 2010	2010	P>1. Wood density is considered a key functional trait influencing the growth and survival of woody plants and has been shown to be related to a slow-fast rate-of-living continuum. Wood density is, however, an emergent trait arising from several vascular properties of wood, including the diameter and frequency of xylem conduits.2. We aimed to test the hypotheses that there is a set of inter-related trade-offs linked to the different functions of wood, that these trade-offs have direct consequences for tree growth and survival and that these trade-offs underlie the observed correlations between wood density and demographic rates. We evaluated the covariation between xylem anatomical traits among woody species of New Zealand and whether that covariation had the potential to constrain variation in wood density and demographic rates.3. Several xylem traits were strongly correlated with each other, but wood density was not correlated with any of them. We also found no significant relationships between wood density and growth or mortality rate. Instead, growth was strongly related to xylem traits associated with hydraulic capacity (conduit diameter and a conductivity index) and to maximum height, whereas mortality rate was strongly correlated only with maximum height. The diameter and frequency of conduits exhibited a significant negative relationship, suggesting a trade-off, which restricted variation in wood density and growth rate, but not mortality rate.4. Our results suggest, for woody species in New Zealand, that growth rate is more closely linked to xylem traits determining hydraulic conductance, rather than wood density. We also found no evidence that denser woods conferred higher survival, or that risk of cavitation caused by wide conduits increased mortality.5. In summary, we found little support for the idea that wood density is a good proxy for position along a fast-slow rate-of-living continuum. Instead, the strong, negative relationship between vessel diameter and frequency may constrain the realized diversity of demographic niches of tree species in New Zealand. Trade-offs in function therefore have the potential to shape functional diversity and ecology of forest communities by linking selection on structure and function to population-level dynamics.									28	0	27	0	29	0269-8463		WOS:000274952600002		J	Tsuchiya, Ryouta; Furukawa, Ikuo								SYNCHRONIZED MATURATION OF VESSEL DIAMETER AND RAY WIDTH IN ZELKOVA SERRATA								IAWA JOURNAL				31	3			269	282					2010	2010	This study describes radial variation in fibre length, vessel element length, vessel lumen diameter, and ray width (number of cells) in relation to the developmental stages in radial stem increment in Zelkova serrata trees. Maturation age (the age at which the size of the wood elements is stabilized) was compared to the ages at the boundary between the early and middle stages (age t(1)), and the middle and late stages (age t(2)) of radial stem increment. The maturation age was estimated by nonlinear segmented regression analysis. Ages t(1) and t(2) were estimated by the Gompertz growth function. The maturation age for the length of axial elements (wood fibres and vessel elements) was not related to either age t(1) or age t(2). However, the maturation ages for vessel lumen diameter and ray width were close, and both were related to age t(2). This indicates that the maturation of vessel lumen diameter and ray width was synchronized and both were related to the stage of radial stem increment.									1	0	1	0	1	0928-1541		WOS:000281696000004		J	Sisi, Davod Efhami; Karimi, Almaghi; Pourtahmasi, Kambiz; Taghiyari, Hamid Reza; Asadi, Farshad								THE EFFECTS OF AGROFORESTRY PRACTICES ON VESSEL PROPERTIES IN POPULUS NIGRA VAR BETULIFOLIA								IAWA JOURNAL				31	4			481	487					2010	2010	The effects of intercropping with alfalfa and initial tree spacing on vessel diameter and frequency in Populus nigra var betulifolia are reported, on the basis of a study of fifteen trees Material was harvested from an agroforestry trial near Karaj city, Iran Treatments included four initial spacings between poplar trees intercropped with alfalfa as a nitrogen-fixing plant, as well as one control treatment without alfalfa Intercropping with alfalfa as well as increasing initial spacing had a positive effect on growth rate which in turn affected the diameter and frequency of the vessels Intercropping with alfalfa resulted in increased vessel diameter and frequency, while wider initial spacing decreased the vessel frequency (VF), and to some extent the vessel lumen area percentage (VLA%), but increased vessel lumen diameter (VLD)									1	0	0	0	1	0928-1541		WOS:000284991300008		J	Poorter, Lourens; McDonald, Imole; Alarcon, Alfredo; Fichtler, Esther; Licona, Juan-Carlos; Pena-Claros, Marielos; Sterck, Frank; Villegas, Zulma; Sass-Klaassen, Ute								The importance of wood traits and hydraulic conductance for the performance and life history strategies of 42 rainforest tree species								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				185	2			481	492		10.1111/j.1469-8137.2009.03092.x			2010	2010	P>In a comparative study of 42 rainforest tree species we examined relationships amongst wood traits, diameter growth and survival of large trees in the field, and shade tolerance and adult stature of the species.The species show two orthogonal axes of trait variation: a primary axis related to the vessel size-number trade-off (reflecting investment in hydraulic conductance vs hydraulic safety) and a secondary axis related to investment in parenchyma vs fibres (storage vs strength). Across species, growth rate was positively related to vessel diameter and potential specific hydraulic conductance (K(p)), and negatively related to wood density. Survival rate was only positively related to wood density.Light-demanding species were characterized by low wood and vessel density and wide vessels. Tall species were characterized by wide vessels with low density and large K(p). Hydraulic traits were more closely associated with adult stature than with light demand, possibly because tall canopy species experience more drought stress and face a higher cavitation risk.Vessel traits affect growth and wood density affects growth and survival of large trees in the field. Vessel traits and wood density are therefore important components of the performance and life history strategies of tropical tree species.									93	2	92	1	96	0028-646X		WOS:000272893800013	19925555	J	Sellin, Arne; Rohejaerv, Andrus; Rahi, Maert								Distribution of vessel size, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown of silver birch (Betula pendula)								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				22	2			205	216		10.1007/s00468-007-0177-4			APR 2008	2008	Spatial patterns in vessel diameter, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown were examined in closed-canopy trees of silver birch (Betula pendula). The variation in anatomical and hydraulic characteristics of branches was considered from three perspectives: vertically within a crown (lower, middle and upper crown), radially along main branches (proximal, middle and distal part), and with respect to branch orders (first-, second- and third-order branches). Hydraulically weighted mean diameter of vessels (D (h)) and theoretical specific conductivity of the xylem (k (t)) exhibited no vertical trend within the tree crown, whereas leaf-specific conductivity of the xylem (LSCt) decreased acropetally. Variation in LSCt was governed by sapwood area to leaf area ratio (Huber value) rather than by changes in xylem anatomy. The acropetal increase in soil-to-leaf conductance (G (T)) within the birch canopy is attributable to longer path length within the lower-crown branches and higher hydraulic resistance of the shade leaves. D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, while vessel density (VD) and relative area of vessel lumina (VA) increased distally along main branches. A strong negative relationship between vessel diameter and VD implies a trade-off between hydraulic efficiency and mechanical stability of xylem. D (h) and VD combined explained 85.4% of the total variation of k (t) in the regression model applied to the whole data set. Xylem in fast-growing branches (primary branches) had greater area of vessel lumina per unit cross-sectional area of sapwood, resulting in a positive relationship between branch radial growth rate and k (t). D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, whereas VD increased with increasing branch order. This pattern promotes the hydraulic dominance of primary branches over the secondary branches and their dominance over tertiary branches. In this way crown architecture contributes to preferential water flow along the main axes, potentially providing better water supply for the branch apical bud and foliage located in the outer, better-insolated part of the crown.									14	1	12	0	15	0931-1890		WOS:000254240300009		J	Fonti, Patrick; Solomonoff, Natalie; Garcia-Gonzalez, Ignacio				Fonti, Patrick/B-7400-2011	Fonti, Patrick/0000-0002-7070-3292			Earlywood vessels of Castanea sativa record temperature before their formation								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				173	3			562	570		10.1111/j.1469-8137.2006.01945.x			2007	2007	The aim of this study was to identify the climatic signal contained in the earlywood vessel size of the ring-porous chestnut (Castanea sativa) and the physiological processes involved in the underlying mechanisms.In order to assign the encoded signal to a specific physiological process, bud phenology and vessel formation were monitored along an elevation transect and chronologies of the size of the first row of earlywood vessels were retrospectively correlated with 40 yr of early spring temperatures.The first vessels appeared in late April to early May, after encoding both a negative temperature signal in February-March (during tree quiescence) and a positive temperature signal in early April (at the time of resumption of shoot growth).We hypothesize that February and March temperatures affect cambial sensitivity to auxin, preconditioning tree responses later in the season. Furthermore, April temperature is related to tree activation whereby new hormone production fosters vessel expansion.									53	2	42	0	54	0028-646X		WOS:000243478900013	17244050	J	Schmitz, Nele; Verheyden, Anouk; Beeckman, Hans; Gitundu Kairo, James; Koedam, Nico								Influence of a salinity gradient on the vessel characters of the mangrove species Rhizophora mucronata								ANNALS OF BOTANY				98	6			1321	1330		10.1093/aob/mcl224			DEC 2006	2006	Background and Aims Although mangroves have been extensively studied, little is known about their ecological wood anatomy. This investigation examined the potential use of vessel density as a proxy for soil water salinity in the mangrove species Rhizophora mucronata (Rhizophoraceae) from Kenya.Methods In a time-standardized approach, 50 wood discs from trees growing in six salinity categories were investigated. Vessel densities, and tangential and radial diameters of rainy and dry season wood of one distinct year, at three positions on the stem discs, were measured. A repeated-measures ANOVA with the prevailing salinity was performed.Key Results Vessel density showed a significant increase with salinity, supporting its use as a prospective measure of salinity. Interestingly, the negative salinity response of the radial diameter of vessels was less striking, and tangential diameter was constant under the varying environmental conditions. An effect of age or growth rate or the presence of vessel dimorphism could be excluded as the cause of the absence of any ecological trend.Conclusions The clear trend in vessel density with salinity, together with the absence of a growth rate and age effect, validates the potential of vessel density as an environmental proxy. However, it can only be used as a relative measure of salinity given that other environmental variables such as inundation frequency have an additional influence on vessel density. With view to a reliable, absolute proxy, future research should focus on finding wood anatomical features correlated exclusively with soil water salinity or inundation frequency. The plasticity in vessel density with differing salinity suggests a role in the establishment of a safe water transport system. To confirm this hypothesis, the role of inter-vessel pits, their relationship to the rather constant vessel diameter and the underlying physiology and cell biology needs to be examined.									20	0	20	0	21	0305-7364		WOS:000242245400021	17062590	J	Kondoh, S; Yahata, H; Nakashizuka, T; Kondoh, M								Interspecific variation in vessel size, growth and drought tolerance of broad-leaved trees in semi-arid regions of Kenya								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				26	7			899	904					JUL 2006	2006	In semi-arid regions, trees often wither during the dry season. Withering is sometimes manifest as die-back, whereby whithering results in shoot death, which progresses downward from the uppermost part of the crown. In this study, we measured the relationships between height growth and diameter at breast height, die-back frequency and severity, vessel size and specific hydraulic conductivity of four evergreen (Senna siamea (Lamk) H.S. Irwin & Barneby, Jacaranda mimosifolia D. Don, Azadirachta indica A.H.L. Juss and Acacia gerrardii Benth.) and one deciduous (Melia volkensii Gurke) plantation tree species in Kenya, which has a conspicuous dry season. Die-back occurred readily in some species, but not in others. Senna siamea showed the highest specific hydraulic conductivity and the highest growth rate among the five species and was quite susceptible to die-back. Among species, height growth and specific hydraulic conductivity were positively correlated with vessel size and negatively correlated with die-back frequency, suggesting a trade-off between growth rate and drought tolerance. This implies that an adaptation to rapid Growth under humid conditions leads to low drought tolerance. However, the deciduous tree Melia volkensii showed high specific hydraulic conductivity and growth, with no symptoms of die-back, implying that a mechanism associated with the deciduous habit results in drought avoidance by reducing the requirement for water during the dry season.									12	0	10	0	12	0829-318X		WOS:000238628500006	16585035	J	Ohshima, J; Yokota, S; Yoshizawa, N; Ona, T								Representative heights for assessing whole-tree values and the within-tree variations of derived wood properties in Eucalyptus camaldulensis and E-globulus								WOOD AND FIBER SCIENCE				37	1			51	65					JAN 2005	2005	The representative heights in the trunk to indicate whole-tree values and the within-tree variations of derived wood properties, namely flexibility coefficient, wall coverage ratio, vessel diameter radial/tangential (R/T) ratio, fiber diameter R/T ratio, and fiber coarseness, were examined in Eucalyptus camaldulensis and E. globulus trees. In both species, within-tree variations were generally observed as high in the upper and outer parts of the trunk for wall coverage ratio and in the lower pans for flexibility coefficient and vessel diameter R/T ratio. In E. camaldulensis, within-tree variations were observed as high in the upper and outer parts of the trunk for fiber coarseness, and in the lower and inner parts for fiber diameter R/T ratio. In E. globulus, within-tree variations were observed as high in the outer pans for fiber coarseness. but fiber diameter R/T ratio had no clear trend. The representative height assessing the derived wood properties was 2.8 m in E. camaldulensis and 1.8 m in E. globulus, regardless of differences in tree height (growth rate)No representative height was found for wall coverage ratio.									1	0	0	0	1	0735-6161		WOS:000226339700006		J	Woodrum, CL; Ewers, FW; Telewski, FW								Hydraulic, biomechanical, and anatomical interactions of xylem from five species of Acer (Aceraceae)								AMERICAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY				90	5			693	699		10.3732/ajb.90.5.693			MAY 2003	2003	Possible trade-offs between hydraulic conductivity and mechanical properties of woody stems from five species were assessed. Acer negundo is a ruderal tree, A. saccharinum, and A. rubrum are fast-growing and shade-intolerant soft maples, whereas A. nigrum and A. saccharum are slow-growing and shade-tolerant hard maples. It was hypothesized that the ruderal and soft maples would have lower modulus of elasticity (MOE) and modulus of rupture (MOR), but higher maximum specific conductivity (K-s max) than hard maples. Many anatomical and general morphological characteristics were measured in an attempt to correlate them to water transport and/or mechanical strength differences between species. No difference was found between species in vessel diameter, fiber wall thickness, initial hydraulic conductivity (K-h initial), specific conductivity (K-s max), native percent embolism, or Huber value. Similarly, no trade-off was found between K-s max and MOE or MOR across the genus. However, fiber lumen diameter was inversely correlated to MOE and MOR. Surprisingly, percentage of ray parenchyma was positively related to MOE. The results suggest transport/mechanical trade-offs do not occur in Acer and differences in mechanical properties may be due to fiber lumen differences that do not influence the efficient transport of water.									26	0	27	0	28	0002-9122		WOS:000183133400004	21659164	J	Bhat, KM; Priya, PB; Rugmini, P								Characterisation of juvenile wood in teak								WOOD SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY				34	6			517	532					FEB 2001	2001	Juvenile wood properties are studied in a ring-porous tropical hardwood - teak (Tectona grandis L. F), to assess the utilisation potential of short rotation timber. Compared to mature wood, it is characterised by wide rings, short fibres, small diameter, low vessel percentage, high cell wall, wide microfibrillar angle and relatively low or almost similar mechanical properties. While the average modulus of elasticity and modulus of rupture in juvenile wood are 85% and 82% respectively of the mature wood value, the longitudinal compression strength is similar. With relatively small fibrillar angle of 15 degrees and the scope for genetic selection of individual trees, teak juvenile wood has potential for desired dimensional stability. The segmented regression models and visual interpretation of radial patterns of variation in anatomical properties reveal that juvenility in plantation grown teak extends up to 15, 20-25 years depending on the property, growth rate and individual tree and plantation site. The fitted regression models, to explain the age-related variations in juvenile wood properties range from simple, linear to exponential, reciprocal and quadratic equations. Fibre length, microfibrillar angle, Vessel diameter/percentage and ring width appear to be the best anatomical indicators of age demarcation between juvenile and mature wood, although maturation age often varies among the properties. The projected figures for proportion of juvenile wood in plantation grown teak at breast height are 80-100% and 25% at ages 20 and 60 years respectively.									52	1	27	7	57	0043-7719		WOS:000167535000007		J	Schubert, A; Lovisolo, C; Peterlunger, E				Lovisolo, Claudio/A-6610-2010	Lovisolo, Claudio/0000-0001-8825-2904			Shoot orientation affects vessel size, shoot hydraulic conductivity and shoot growth rate in Vitis vinifera L.								PLANT CELL AND ENVIRONMENT				22	2			197	204		10.1046/j.1365-3040.1999.00384.x			FEB 1999	1999	Vitis vinifera L. plants were grown in containers and each plant's single shoot was orientated upwards or downwards. Some plants were trained first upwards, then downwards, then again upwards (N-shaped plants). Vegetative growth was reduced in plants trained downwards compared to that in upward and N-shaped plants. Shoot growth rate slowed in downward shoot portions, but only after the apex had grown downwards for at least 10 internodes. Shoot hydraulic conductivity k(h), measured after elimination of xylem embolisms, was lower in downward than in upward plants. In N-shaped plants k(h) was higher in the upward-growing shoot portions, and lower in the central, downward-growing portion. Shoot-and leaf-specific conductivities were also lower in downward than in upward shoot portions. Xylem cross-sectional area and xylem structure (number of wedges, number of vessels per unit xylem area) differed little in the three orientations. In contrast, vessel diameter and the sum of vessel cross-sectional areas were significantly smaller in downward than in upward shoot portions. These differences could explain the reduction in conductivity observed in the downward-orientated shoot portions. The measurements taken on N-shaped plants showed that the decreases in k(h) and in vessel size were a result of shoot orientation, not shoot bending.									18	0	12	1	18	0140-7791		WOS:000080742500008	11542249	B	Cornelissen, JHC; Castro-Diez, P; Carnelli, AL				Castro, Pilar/L-4716-2014		Lambers, H; Poorter, H; VanVuren, MMI		Variation in relative growth rate among woody species								INHERENT VARIATION IN PLANT GROWTH: PHYSIOLOGICAL MECHANISMS AND ECOLOGICAL CONSEQUENCES								363	392					1998	1998	This chapter searches for consistent patterns in the innate growth rate of woody plant species. To this aim we use a large database with innate seedling mean relative growth rates (RGR) for 97 European woody species. Before we considered it legitimate to scale up from the species level, we first addressed some potential pitfalls due to plant analysis and RGR definition. Subsequently we evaluated the roles of seed reserves and ontogeny/allometry; the possible risks of extrapolation to other (natural) environments; and the role of intraspecific variation in innate mean RGR. None of these factors appeared to affect the broad RGR ranking of the species seriously. Close correlates of seedling mean RGR among woody species were leaf area ratio (LAR) as well as both LAR components, specific leaf area and leaf mass ratio. We then scaled up to larger species assemblages, focusing first on higher taxa and functional types. Higher taxa, life-form, leaf habit, xylem type, life strategy and successional status could each explain part of the interspecific variation in mean RGR. In many cases the contributions of individual factors could be teased out by holding other factors constant, or using phylogenetically independent contrasts. Some of the consistent findings were as follows: woody species belonging to more advanced dicot families grew innately faster than more primitive ones; angiosperm trees faster than gymnosperm trees; deciduous species faster than evergreens; woody climbers and scramblers faster than self-supporting life-forms; shrubs and subshrubs faster than trees; trees with bud-break early in spring and indeterminate shoot growth faster than trees with delayed phenology and determinate shoot growth. This was to some extent correlated with the xylem Vessel size distribution. Trees with ruderal features grew innately faster than more competitive trees, followed by relatively stress-tolerant trees. Pioneer trees tended to grow innately faster than late-successional ones. Then, we tentatively scaled up from innate seedling mean RGR to ecosystem properties. Mediated by nutrient conservation through leaf longevity and anti-herbivore defences, (often evergreen) slow-growing species were found to produce more persistent litter than (often deciduous) fast-growing ones. This could have implications for nutrient turn-over rates in ecosystems. Finally, the woody flora from western Europe's cool-temperate climate belt grew inherently faster than that from a woody flora in the Mediterranean belt, and perhaps faster than that from the Boreal belt.					Workshop on Inherent Variation in Plant Growth Rate	JUN, 1997	Utrecht Univ, Fac Biol; Federat European Soc Plant Physiol; Royal Netherlands Acad Arts & Sci; Backhuys Publ, Leiden; Utrecht Univ, Ecophysiol Res Grp	UTRECHT UNIV, UTRECHT, NETHERLANDS	53	0	51	0	55		90-73348-96-X	WOS:000076263300020		J	Lei, HA; Gartner, BL; Milota, MR								Effect of growth rate on the anatomy, specific gravity, and bending properties of wood from 7-year-old red alder (Alnus rubra)								CANADIAN JOURNAL OF FOREST RESEARCH-REVUE CANADIENNE DE RECHERCHE FORESTIERE				27	1			80	85		10.1139/cjfr-27-1-80			JAN 1997	1997	Understanding the association between growth rate and wood properties is of practical importance to maximizing and sustaining wood and fiber production. Anatomical characteristics, specific gravity, and bending properties were determined at breast height for thirty 7-year-old trees with varying growth rates, from a red alder (Alnus rubra Bong.) plantation. Wood was sampled from the growth ring with a cambial age of 5 years. Growth varied from 2.0 to 9.3 mm/year (ring width), or 264 to 3350 mm(2)/year (ring area). We analyzed the relationship between growth rate, in terms of both annual ring width and area, and each wood property. Because both measures of growth rate yielded the same qualitative results, we only used ring width in our analyses. Regression analysis showed that growth rate had no effect on specific gravity, the modulus of elasticity in bending, the modulus of rupture in bending, fiber diameter, or the proportion of growth ring that was fiber or vessel. Fiber length, vessel diameter, and ray proportion, however, were positively correlated with growth rate. Fiber-wall thickness and axial parenchyma proportion decreased slightly with growth rate. The results indicate that the growth rate of A. rubra trees can be increased through silvicultural practices with few negative effects on wood and fiber quality, at least in the juvenile wood zone of the stem.									15	3	9	0	20	0045-5067		WOS:A1997XD79000011		J	Lei, H; Milota, MR; Gartner, BL								Between- and within-tree variation in the anatomy and specific gravity of wood in Oregon white oak (Quercus garryana Dougl)								IAWA JOURNAL				17	4			445	461					1996	1996	In order to analyze the variation in wood properties within and between trees of an underutilized tree species, we sampled six Oregon white oak (Quercus garryana Dougl.) trees from an 80-year old mixed stand of Q. garryana and Douglas-fir (Pseudotsuga menziesii [Mirb.] France) in the Coast Range of Western Oregon, USA. Fibre length, earlywood vessel diameter, tissue proportions, and specific gravity were measured on samples across the diameter at two heights. Trees had a slight lean (2-12 degrees), so we sampled separately both radii of a diametric strip that ran from the lower to upper side of lean.Variation between trees, between the two heights, and between the lower and upper sides of lean was not significant for most measured wood characteristics. The exceptions were vessel proportion, higher at the upper height, and specific gravity, higher at breast height (P < 0.05). There was significant variation (P < 0.05) between the youngest juvenile wood (growth rings 2, 4, and 7) and the oldest sampled mature wood (growth rings 32, 39, and 48) in fibre length (1.1 vs. 1.2 mm); earlywood vessel diameter (164 vs. 272 mu m), proportion of fibre (64 vs. 46%), vessel (12 vs. 27%), and axial parenchyma (10 vs. 14%); and specific gravity (0.83 vs. 0.66). These characteristics showed demarcation ages between juvenile and mature wood of 10-26 years, depending on the characteristic. The ray proportion (about 14%) showed no definite pattern of radial change. The results of this study may be used for estimating wood and fibre quality of ring-porous hardwoods such as this species.									29	0	24	0	30	0928-1541		WOS:A1996WC11200007		J	MALAN F S								VARIATION ASSOCIATION AND INHERITANCE OF JUVENILE WOOD PROPERTIES OF EUCALYPTUS-GRANDIS HILL EX MAIDEN WITH SPECIAL REFERENCE TO THE EFFECT OF RATE OF GROWTH								South African Forestry Journal					157			16	23					1991	1991	In South Africa existing knowledge on the properties of the juvenile wood of Eucalyptus grandis, their variation and intercorrelation is seriously lacking and not in accordance with the species commercial importance. Such information is important because of the fact that a large proportion of this species is grown under intensive short-rotation management for the production of mining timber and pulpwood. In this study the intercorrelation between wood properties, the variation among families and the effect of growth rate on these properties were studed in 216 young trees sampled from a full-sib diallel progeny trial consisting of 72 families established in the Eastern Transvaal by the Department of Environment Affairs. Results of a factor analysis indicated that the variations in the basic wood properties of young E. grandis is adequately described by studying wood density, fibre lengths and vessel properties such as size, frequency and fractional volume. All these properties vary significantly among families suggesting some genetic influence. Heritability estimates obtained for density, fibre length and vessel diameter are more or less similar in magnitude to those found in previous studies. This, as a number of other studies, indicated no significant or practically important phenotypic correlation between growth rate and wood properties. On the other hand, significant negative genetic correlations of rate of growth with wood density and fibre length were found, although the esimates obtained were considerably less than previously calculated.									1	0	0	1	1	0038-2167		BCI:BCI199293099099		J	WILKES, J								VARIATIONS IN WOOD ANATOMY WITHIN SPECIES OF EUCALYPTUS								IAWA BULLETIN				9	1			13	23					1988	1988										37	1	21	10	44	0254-3915		WOS:A1988M962500002		J	MCKIMM, RJ; ILIC, Y								CHARACTERISTICS OF THE WOOD OF YOUNG FAST-GROWN TREES OF EUCALYPTUS-NITENS MAIDEN WITH SPECIAL REFERENCE TO PROVENANCE VARIATION .3. ANATOMICAL AND PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS								AUSTRALIAN FOREST RESEARCH				17	1			19	28					1987	1987										14	0	5	0	15	0004-914X		WOS:A1987J581000003		J	BAAS, P; CHENGLEE, L; ZHANG, XY; CUI, KI; DENG, YF								SOME EFFECTS OF DWARF GROWTH ON WOOD STRUCTURE								IAWA BULLETIN				5	1			45	63					1984	1984										15	2	13	0	18	0254-3915		WOS:A1984SF07200004		