PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	da Costa Azevedo, Gracilene Fernandes								Photosynthetic parameters and growth in seedlings of Bertholletia excelsa and Carapa guianensis response to pre-acclimation to full sunlight and mild water stress								ACTA AMAZONICA				44	1			67	77					MAR 2014	2014	Light and water are important factors that may limit the growth and development of higher plants. The aim of this study was to evaluate photosynthetic parameters and growth in seedlings of Bertholletia excelsa and Carapa guianensis in response to pre-acclimation to full sunlight and mild water stress. I used six independent pre-acclimation treatments (0, 90 (11h15-12h45), 180 (10h30-13h30), 360 (09h00-15h00), 540 (07h30-16h30) and 720 min (06h00-18h00)) varying the time of exposure to full sunlight (PFS) during 30 days, followed by whole-day outdoor exposure for 120 days. Before PFS, the plants were kept in a greenhouse at low light levels (0.8 mol m(-2) day(-1)). The PFS of 0 min corresponded to plants constantly kept under greenhouse conditions. From the beginning to the end of the experiment, each PFS treatment was submitted to two water regimes: moderate water stress (MWS, pre-dawn leaf water potential (Psi(L)) of -500 to -700 kPa) and without water stress (WWS, Psi(L) of-300 kPa, soil kept at field capacity). Plants under MWS received only a fraction of the amount of water applied to the well-watered ones. At the end of the 120-day-period under outdoor conditions, I evaluated light saturated photosynthesis (A(max)), stomatal conductance (g(s)), transpiration (E) and plant growth. Both A(max) and g(s) were higher for all plants under the PFS treatment. Stem diameter growth rate and A(max) were higher for C. guianensis subjected to MWS than in well-watered plants. The contrary was true for B. excelsa. The growth of seedlings was enhanced by exposure to full sunlight for 180 minutes in both species. However, plants of B. excelsa were sensitive to moderate water stress. The higher photosynthetic rates and faster growth of C. guianensis under full sun and moderate water stress make this species a promissory candidate to be tested in reforestation programs.									0	0	0	0	0	0044-5967		WOS:000327804500007		J	Gyimah, Richard; Nakao, Toshio								Early growth and photosynthetic responses to light in seedlings of three tropical species differing in successional strategies								NEW FORESTS				33	3			217	236		10.1007/s11056-006-9028-1			MAY 2007	2007	Containerized seedlings of three commercially important tropical species were grown under four different light treatments [i.e., 100 ( open site), 45, 22 and 10% sunlight] for 130 days. Light-saturated photosynthesis (A(max)) and light saturation estimates (LSE) reflected the species successional status with Terminalia superba Engl. and Diels, the pioneer species showing largest mean Amax and LSE at 100% sunlight, whereas at 10% sunlight, it showed the lowest A(max) and LSE. At 22% sunlight, Cedrela odorata L., an intermediate successional species had greater Amax and LSE than Mansonia altissima A. Chev., a non-pioneer light demander and T. superba. T. superba had the lowest relative growth rate (RGR) at 10% sunlight and greatest net assimilation rate (NAR) at 100% sunlight; although a higher RGR at this light level was not seen for this species. Strong and positive linear mean A(max)-mean NAR relationship of C. odorata and T. superba indicated that differences in leaf photosynthetic rates of the two species were reflected in their NAR, which increased with increasing light. At final harvest, superior biomass production was found at 45% sunlight for all the species. Seedling responses in specific leaf area, leaf area ratio, leaf mass ratio and root mass ratio were typically those found along a light gradient. At the 100% sunlight, intrinsic water-use efficiency (WUE), F-v/F-m and final root system of the plants was generally superior in T. superba but at 10% sunlight, WUE was inferior in T. superba when compared to C. odorata and M. altissima, reflecting the respective species' short-term acclimation to high or low light. Results of this study may have practical use in screening tropical tree species for use in plantation forestry.									7	1	6	0	8	0169-4286		WOS:000245361100001		J	Dalling, JW; Winter, K; Hubbell, SP								Variation in growth responses of neotropical pioneers to simulated forest gaps								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				18	5			725	736		10.1111/j.0269-8463.2004.00868.x			OCT 2004	2004	1. One proposed mechanism by which tree species coexist is through partitioning gradients of light availability. We performed a pot experiment in which seedlings of 12 pioneer species were established in 30% light, then transplanted to six light treatments designed to simulate natural gaps ranging from 25 m(2) (approximate to10% full sun) to 800 m(2) (60% full sun). Plants were harvested after 56-117 days, and comparisons were made of allocation patterns and growth and carbon assimilation rates.2. Species varied strongly in their maximum relative growth rate (RGR, range 15.4-83.6 mg g(-1) day(-1)). However, we found little evidence for gap-size partitioning based on growth rate, as species RGR in large and small simulated gaps was strongly correlated (r = 0.83, P < 0.001).3. Species differences in growth reflected variation in both physiology and allocation. Net assimilation rate was a strong determinant of RGR across all simulated gap sizes (r(2) = 0.60-0.71, P < 0.001). Leaf area ratio was a poor predictor of growth rate under all gap sizes (r(2) = 0.04-0.08, NS).4. The maximum rate of net C assimilation (A(max)) increased significantly with simulated gap size for all but one pioneer species, but only when measured on a per area basis. Among species variation in A(max) was only weakly related to RGR. Foliar nitrogen concentration varied widely among species (range 2.2-4.7% dry mass), but was only weakly correlated with RGR (r(2) = 0.04-0.30).5. Previous growth analyses of tropical seedlings have identified both specific leaf area (SLA) and seed mass as key traits correlated with growth rate. Although SLA varied twofold and seed mass more than a thousand-fold among the pioneer species in this study, neither trait was significantly correlated with among-species variation in RGR. Although these traits underlie major differences in life history between shade-tolerant and pioneer species, they contribute little to variation in growth performance within the pioneer functional group.									30	1	31	0	32	0269-8463		WOS:000224000900014		J	Lusk, CH; Wright, I; Reich, PB								Photosynthetic differences contribute to competitive advantage of evergreen angiosperm trees over evergreen conifers in productive habitats								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				160	2			329	336		10.1046/j.1469-8137.2003.00879.x			NOV 2003	2003	Here we explore the possible role of leaf-level gas exchange traits in determining growth rate differences and competitive interactions between evergreen angiosperms and conifers.We compared relationships among photosynthetic capacity (A(max)), maximum ad stomatal conductance (G(s)), leaf life span, nitrogen concentration (N) and specific leaf area (SLA), in sun leaves of 23 evergreen angiosperm and 20 conifer populations.Despite similar average leaf N(mass), conifer leaves lived longer on average (36 months) than angiosperms (25 months). At a standardized leaf N, A(mass) was higher in angiosperms (56 nmol g(-1) s(-1)) than in conifers (36 nmol g(-1) s(-1)). Stepwize regression suggested that most of this difference in photosynthetic nitrogen use efficiency could be explained by G(s) and SLA. Mean G(s) (on an area basis) of angiosperms was higher than that of conifers (152 vs 117 mmol m(2) s(-1)), but A(area)-G(s) relationships were similar for the two groups. At a given leaf N, conifers had lower SLA (projected area basis) than angiosperms.Photosynthetic differences probably contribute to the competitive advantage of angiosperm trees over conifers in productive habitats, and may be linked to the greater hydraulic capacity of vessels, enabling angiosperms to develop higher stomatal conductance and therefore sustain higher transpiration rates.									41	1	45	0	46	0028-646X		WOS:000186322000006		J	Close, DC; Beadle, CL				beadle, chris/C-9390-2011				Chilling-dependent photoinhibition, nutrition and growth analysis of Eucalyptus nitens seedlings during establishment								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				23	4			217	226					MAR 2003	2003	Effects of chilling-dependent photoinhibition on gas exchange, chlorophyll fluorescence, growth and nutrition of Eucalyptus nitens (Deane and Maiden) Maiden seedlings were assessed for 70 weeks after transplanting 9-month-old seedlings in early winter. One month before transplanting, the seedlings were assigned to fertilized or nutrient-deprived treatments. Immediately after transplanting, half the seedlings in each nutrient treatment were placed in shadecloth tree shelters. The experimental site was at an altitude of 700 m, which is considered marginal for the establishment of E. nitens plantations in Tasmania because of low mean annual minimum temperatures.Overnight frosts followed by sunny morning conditions in the first 20 weeks after transplanting (early June to early October) caused severe photoinhibition. Predawn maximal photochemical efficiency (F-v/F-m) and maximum net photosynthesis (A(max)) Were depressed in nutrient-deprived seedlings compared with fertilized seedlings, although shading partially alleviated this difference. Neither F-v/F-m nor A(max) recovered to values observed before transplanting until > 20 weeks after transplanting. During this period, non-photochemical quenching (NPQ) was high in seedlings in all treatments, although NPQ was lower in shaded, fertilized seedlings than in seedlings in the other treatments.Total foliar nitrogen (N) concentration increased up to 42 weeks after transplanting in the nutrient-deprived seedlings in parallel with increasing relative growth rate (RGR). Fractionation of N- and phosphorus (P)-containing compounds indicated that differences in protein N accounted for the treatment differences in total seedling N. Nucleic acid P increased and inorganic P decreased during growth periods, although total seedling P remained constant. Among treated seedlings, height growth was greatest in shaded seedlings: this was probably a result of apical dominance effects because RGR was higher in unshaded seedlings than in shaded seedlings. Thus, the shade treatment alleviated chilling-dependent photoinhibition and maximized growth during winter, but limited growth during warmer periods and therefore overall growth.									13	0	10	2	14	0829-318X		WOS:000181841200001	12566257	J	Fetene, M; Feleke, Y								Growth and photosynthesis of seedlings of four tree species from a dry tropical afromontane forest					2			JOURNAL OF TROPICAL ECOLOGY				17				269	283					MAR 2001	2001	Growth, photosynthesis and carbon allocation pattern were studied in four dry afromontane forest tree species (Olea europea subspecies cuspidata, Podocarpus falcatus, Hagenia abyssinica and Juniperus procera) under varied light regimes in a greenhouse. The objective of the study was to assess the potential of the species for growth under forest canopies and to identify their habitat preferences. The light regimes were created using shade cloth and the) corresponded with deep forest understoreys (2% of the light in the open gap); moderate shade (10%), slight shade as is found in edges of forest gaps (20%) and 100% representing open gaps. Seedling biomass was significantly influenced by light regimes for all species as were total leaf area and relative growth rate. H. abyssinica had the highest growth rate but the lowest survival rate in shade. There was a consistent trend for higher specific leaf area (SLA) and leaf area ratio (LAR) at lower growth light regimes in O. europea and P. falcatus. O. europea and P. falcatus had similar allocation patterns whereby between 20-40% of the total biomass uas allocated to stem, 20-30% to roots and 50-60% to leaves. In H. abyssinica up to 80% was allocated to leaves and only a small percentage to stem and to roots.Within species there were significant differences in the light saturated rate of photosynthesis (A(max)) per unit area among the plants grown at the lowest light level and in the open. For plants grown in the open there were ver): little among species differences in A,,,, per unit area. However, there were significant differences in the ii,,, of the different species grown at the lowest light level. Chlorophyll fluorescence measurements indicated that open-grown P. falcatus and O. europea experienced moderate photoinhibition. From the growth and photosynthesis results P. falcatus and O. europea appeared to be non-pioneer, shade-tolerant species, while J. procera and to a larger extent H. abyssinica showed pioneer, light-demanding characteristics. The results ar e discussed in terms of the occurrence of the species in the mosaic climaxes of afromontane forests.									18	1	17	1	21	0266-4674		WOS:000167920700008		J	Ellis, AR; Hubbell, SP; Potvin, C								In situ field measurements of photosynthetic rates of tropical tree species: a test of the functional group hypothesis								CANADIAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY-REVUE CANADIENNE DE BOTANIQUE				78	10			1336	1347					OCT 2000	2000	We examined photosynthetic characteristics of 21 tree species from a Panamanian forest differing in successional status. We hypothesized that functional guilds of species, grouped by successional status, would differ in photosynthetic performance and that pioneers would be more sensitive to seasonality and more variable in response to light than intermediate or shade tolerants. Steady-state leaf-level photosynthesis (A) was measured in situ on eight trees per species. Light response curves were generated by fitting a hyperbolic model to these data. Average light saturated photosynthetic rates (A(max)) were then calculated for each species. Variability of light, photosynthesis, and leaf characteristics were quantified using coefficients of variation (CV). Significant differences were detected among species and functional groups for A, A(max), and leaf N concentration. Functional group explained 46% of the observed variation in A. Pioneers exhibited higher light-saturated photosynthetic rates than intermediates; both were higher than shade tolerants. Intermediates were the most seasonally plastic group and had the highest leaf N concentration. Shade tolerants were found in lower, more variable light environments than pioneers. A strong positive correlation between diameter growth rate and photosynthetic rate (r(2) = 0.55, p = 0.004) was observed across species. Our results tend to confirm the hypothesis that physiological traits can be used to differentiate among functional groups of plants. However, no evidence was found for higher plasticity of pioneer compared with shade-tolerant species.									21	2	24	2	27	0008-4026		WOS:000165447300011		J	Oleksyn, J; Zytkowiak, R; Reich, PB; Tjoelker, MG; Karolewski, P				Oleksyn, Jacek/I-4539-2012				Ontogenetic patterns of leaf CO2 exchange, morphology and chemistry in Betula pendula trees								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				14	5			271	281					MAR 2000	2000	In order to explore ontogenetic variation in leaf-level physiological traits of Betula pendula trees, we measured changes in mass- (A(mass)) and area-based (A(area)) net photosynthesis under light-saturated conditions, mass- (RSmass) and area-based (RSarea) leaf respiration, relative growth rate, leaf mass per area (LMA), total nonstructural carbohydrates (TNC), and macro- and micronutrient concentrations. Expanding leaves maintained high rates of A(area) but due to high growth respiration rates, net CO2 fixation occurred only at irradiances >200 mu mol photons m(-2) s(-1). We found that full structural leaf development is not a necessary prerequisite for maintaining positive CO2 balance in young birch leaves. Maximum rates of A(area) were realized in late June and early July, whereas the highest values of A(mass) occurred in May and steadily declined thereafter. The maintenance respiration rate averaged approximate to 8 nmol CO2 g(-1) s(-1), whereas growth respiration varied between 0 and 65 nmol CO2 g(-1) s(-1). After reaching its lowest point in mid-June, leaf respiration increased gradually until the end of the growing season. Mass and area-based dark respiration were significantly positively correlated with LMA at stages of leaf maturity, and senescence. Concentrations of P and K decreased during leaf development and stabilized or increased during maturity, and concentrations of immobile elements such as Ca, Mn and B increased throughout the growing season. Identification of interrelations between leaf development, CO2 exchange, TNC and leaf nutrients allowed us to define factors related to ontogenetic variation in leaf-level physiological traits and can be helpful in establishing periods appropriate for sampling birch leaves for diagnostic purposes such as assessment of plant and site productivity or effects of biotic or abiotic factors.									31	0	29	0	32	0931-1890		WOS:000086380200005		J	Morecroft, MD; Roberts, JM								Photosynthesis and stomatal conductance of mature canopy Oak (Quercus robur) and Sycamore (Acer pseudoplatanus) trees throughout the growing season								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				13	3			332	342		10.1046/j.1365-2435.1999.00327.x			JUN 1999	1999	1. Gas exchange is strongly seasonal in temperate deciduous forests; however, virtually no studies have described measurements made at the leaf scale through the whole growing season. This level of detail is important to understanding processes as substantial differences may occur within the canopy between species and between sun and shade leaves.2. Gas exchange was measured weekly throughout the growing season in leaves of Oak (Quercus robur) and Sycamore (Acer pseudoplatanus) trees at Wytham Woods, UK. In Q. robur sun, shade and intermediate leaves were sampled on each occasion.3. Acer pseudoplatanus came into leaf before Q. robur and commenced net assimilation (A) earlier. Maximum irradiance saturated photosynthetic rates (A(max)) in Q. robur were reached approximately 50 days after budburst and were maintained until approximately 20 days before abscission. Acer pseudoplatanus lost its leaves before Q. robur in the autumn and showed no seasonal trend in A(max). The lag between budburst and attainment of maximum photosynthetic rate in Q. robur was substantial and represented a quarter of the potential growing season.4. A(max) of A. pseudoplatanus (3.5 mu mol m(-2) s(-1)) sun leaves was substantially lower than that of Q. robur (10.4 mu mol m(-2) s(-1)) despite A. pseudoplatanus being a fast-growing species. The earlier flushing of A. pseudoplatanus leaves in the spring could not completely compensate for this. It is likely that other variables, such as total leaf area, are responsible for the high growth rate of A. pseudoplatanus, rather than high photosynthetic rates.5. Shade leaves of Q. robur had lower A(max) and mean A than sun leaves; their quantum efficiency was also lower. Consistent with this, sun leaves had a higher nitrogen content per unit area, resulting from a lower specific leaf area (SLA).6. Week to week variations in solar radiation influenced A; this could be described by a non-rectangular hyperbola. Stomatal conductance (g(s)) decreased in conditions of high vapour pressure deficit (VPD). However, this did not decrease A as high VPD was associated with high solar radiation and the stimulation of photosynthesis caused by high photosynthetic photon flux density (PPFD) more than compensated for the reduction by VPD.									49	3	43	0	52	0269-8463		WOS:000081534300006		J	Davies, SJ								Photosynthesis of nine pioneer Macaranga species from Borneo in relation to life history								ECOLOGY				79	7			2292	2308					OCT 1998	1998	Early successional (pioneer) tropical tree species are characterized by a suite of ecophysiological and life history traits; however, little is known of the relationships between these groups of traits, and their consequences for species' distribution patterns in diverse tropical forests. This study investigated leaf-level ecophysiological variation in seedlings of nine sympatric, pioneer tree species of Macaranga (Euphorbiaceae) from Borneo, grown at three light levels (high: similar to 19 mol/d; medium: similar to 7 mol/d; low: similar to 3.6 mol/d). A multivariate analysis of traits associated with species' successional status was used to rank species according to life history variation, and then to investigate patterns of covariation in seedling ecophysiological and life history traits.Ecophysiological traits varied significantly among the nine species. On a leaf area basis, dark respiration (R-d-area) in high-light seedlings ranged from 0.51 to 0.90 mu mol CO2. m(-2).s(-1), and light saturated net photosynthesis (A(max)-area) ranged from 7 to 13 mu mol CO2. m(-2).s(-1). A(max)-mass and R-d-mass were strongly negatively correlated with leaf mass per unit area (LMA). Among species, A(max)-mass and R-d-mass were strongly positively correlated for high-light grown seedlings, reflecting a trade-off between high assimilation rates and respiratory costs.Within species, A(max)-area, R-d-area, g(s), LMA, and photosynthetic light compensation point were significantly greater in high-light grown plants for all species. Due to the high plasticity of LMA, A(max)-mass and R-d-mass were only weakly influenced by light growth conditions, suggesting that resource allocation patterns that maximize photosynthetic ability are critical to survival and growth in low light for these species.Principal components analysis (PCA) of ecophysiological traits for the nine species revealed a continuum of variation from species with relatively low A(max), low g(s), and high LMA to species with the opposite traits. The primary axis of the PCA of life history traits was strongly related to variation in shade tolerance and seed mass. The second life history axis distinguished among the more shade-intolerant species. The PCAs of ecophysiological and life history traits were not completely concordant due to variation in life history traits among high A(max) species. A(max)-mass and LMA, were correlated with a successional ranking of the species. The study shows how a suite of inter-related ecophysiological and life history traits can result in a diversity of pioneer tree ecologies.									46	3	45	0	50	0012-9658		WOS:000076300200007		J	Oleksyn, J; Modrzynski, J; Tjoelker, MG; Zytkowiak, R; Reich, PB; Karolewski, P				Oleksyn, Jacek/I-4539-2012				Growth and physiology of Picea abies populations from elevational transects: common garden evidence for altitudinal ecotypes and cold adaptation								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				12	4			573	590		10.1046/j.1365-2435.1998.00236.x			AUG 1998	1998	1. There are conflicting reports concerning the adaptive features of tree populations originating from cold, high-altitude environments. We hypothesize that such trees will possess adaptive features that will be demonstrated in a common environment, such as elevated rates of net CO2 exchange, elevated needle nitrogen concentration and high proportional biomass allocation to roots. To test this hypothesis we measured tree and seed properties of 54 populations of Norway spruce [Picea abies (L.) Karst.] located along eight altitudinal transects (from c. 600 to 1500 m) in southern Poland. We also measured growth, biomass partitioning, net photosynthetic capacity (A(max)), needle dark respiration (RS) and carbohydrate, nitrogen (N) and chlorophyll concentration of seedlings originating from these populations grown for 2 to 7 years in a common garden at 150 m elevation. Measured in situ along the elevational transects, there were linear declines in seed mass, average d.b.h. and height growth increment of seed trees with increased altitude or lower mean annual temperature.2, In the common garden, the Norway spruce populations from colder, high-altitude habitats had higher N concentration in needles than those from low altitudes. Both A(max) and needle RS increased with altitude of seed origin and were significantly related to needle N concentration. High-altitude populations also had higher concentrations of chlorophyll and carotene than those from low elevations. Despite higher photosynthetic rates in high-altitude populations, seedling height and dry mass in the common garden declined with altitude of seed origin. Proportional dry mass partitioning to roots nearly doubled with increasing altitude of origin, while the length of the shoot-growth period was reduced. The high respiration rates, high allocation to roots and reduced shoot-growth period are probably responsible for the low growth rate potential of high-altitude populations, more than offsetting their higher photosynthetic rates.3, The results of this study showed that Norway spruce populations from cold mountain environments are characterized by several potentially adaptive features. Because these were similar to conifer population responses along a latitudinal gradient of origin, they are probably driven by climate. These climate-driven differences were common to all transects: for a given altitude or mean annual temperature, plant traits were independent of mountain range of origin. However, populations originating from cold high-elevation sites often differed per unit change in altitude or mean annual temperature more than did low elevation populations. The scaling of nitrogen, CO2 exchange and biomass and allocation patterns may be useful in modelling Norway spruce response on montane forest ecosystems under changing environments.									125	11	126	1	143	0269-8463		WOS:000076276900009		J	Huante, P; Rincon, E								Responses to light changes in tropical deciduous woody seedlings with contrasting growth rates								OECOLOGIA				113	1			53	66					JAN 1998	1998	We evaluated the responses in growth, biomass allocation, photosynthesis and stomatal conductance, to changes in light in woody seedlings from the tropical deciduous forest in Mexico, which shows a highly seasonal rain pattern. We studied ten species, which differed by 30-fold in relative growth rate (RGR). We analyzed plant growth in two contrasting light levels during 52 days and two transfers: from high to low (HL) and from low to high (LH) light intensity, and the respective controls in high (HH) and low (LL) light for another 52 days. The photosynthetic capacity (A(max)) and stomatal conductance were measured at the day of the transfer between light conditions and at the end of the experiment. Species with high RGR showed the largest changes in RGR in response to contrasting light conditions (HH/LL ratio), and species with low RGR showed low responses. The fast-growing species were the most plastic, followed by species with intermediate growth rates, with the slow-growing species being the least plastic. Fast-growing species achieved higher maximum photosynthetic capacities (A(max)) and stomatal conductance and higher response to light than slow-growing species. Species with high RGR showed a low RGR HH/LH ratio, suggesting a large response of L plants when transfered to H. The RGR of the species were associated with species specific leaf area and with the response in the leaf area, net assimilation rate and leaf weight ratio, suggesting the importance of the leaf area produced and the leaf characteristics rather than root:shoot ratio in determining RGR. Considering that seed germination is expected at the beginning of the rainy period, seedlings of most of the species will experience high-light conditions during its early growth. There are large annual variations in the time required for canopy closure (35-75 days). The influence of these variations may have different effect on the species studied. Species with intermediate growth rate and intermediate response to light changes were less affected by light reduction than fast-growing species. The intermediate-RGR species Caesalpinia eriostachys is the most abundant and widely distributed species, perhaps this could be in part due to its ability to acclimate to both light increases and decreases. The fast-growing species studied here can be found in open sites in the forest and in areas cleared for pasture growth. These fast-growing species eventually reach the canopy, although this may require several canopy openings during their lives, which implies juvenile shade tolerance. In the tropical deciduous forest juvenile pioneer trees also benefit from the temporary high light available caused by the dry period during the rainy season. The slow-growing species Celaenodendron mexicanum forms small patches of monospecific forest; the adult trees are not completely deciduous, and they retain their old leaves for a long time period before shedding. Thus seedlings of this species may receive lower levels of light, in agreement with its shade tolerance and its lower response to light increases.									44	5	46	1	53	0029-8549		WOS:000071009200006		J	REICH, PB; WALTERS, MB; ELLSWORTH, DS								LEAF LIFE-SPAN IN RELATION TO LEAF, PLANT, AND STAND CHARACTERISTICS AMONG DIVERSE ECOSYSTEMS								ECOLOGICAL MONOGRAPHS				62	3			365	392		10.2307/2937116			SEP 1992	1992	Variation in leaf life-span has long been considered of ecological significance. Despite this, quantitative evaluation of the relationships between leaf life-span and other plant and ecosystem characteristics has been rare. In this paper we ask whether leaf life-span is related to other leaf, plant, and stand traits of species from diverse ecosystems and biomes. We also examine the interaction between leaf, plant, and stand traits and their relation to productivity and ecological patterns.Among all species, both mass- (A(mass)) and area-based (A(area)) maximum net photosynthesis decreased with increasing leaf life-span, but the relationship was stronger on a mass (P < .001, r2 = 0.70) than an area (P < .05, r2 = 0.24) basis. Similarly, mass-based leaf nitrogen (leaf N(mass)) decreased (P < .001, r2 = 0.52) with leaf life-span, but area-based leaf N (leaf N(area)) did not (P > .25, r2 = 0.01). Specific leaf area (SLA, leaf area/leaf dry mass) and leaf diffusive conductance also decreased with increasing leaf life-span. Decreasing A(mass) with increasing leaf life-span results from the impact of decreasing N(mass) and SLA on A(mass). Variation in leaf traits as a function of leaf life-span was similar for broad-leaved and needle-leaved subsets of the data. These leaf-scale data from several biomes were compared to a data set from a single biome, Amazonia. For several leaf traits (e.g., SLA, N(mass), and A(mass)) the quantitative relationship with leaf life-span was similar in the two independent data sets, suggesting that these are fundamental relations applicable to all species. A(mass) was a linear function of N(mass)(P < .001, r2 = 0.74) with a regression similar to previous analyses, while A(area) was not significantly related to N(area). These results suggest that the photosynthesis-leaf N relationship among species should be considered universal when expressed on a mass, but not on a leaf area, basis.Relative growth rates (RGR) and leaf area ratio (LAR, the whole-plant ratio of leaf area to total dry mass) of seedlings decreased with increasing leaf life-span (P < .001, r2 = 0.61 and 0.89, respectively). LAR was positively related to both RGR and A(mass)(r2 = 0.68 and 0.84, respectively), and A(mass) and RGR were also positively related (r2 = 0.55). Absolute height growth rates of young trees decreased with increasing leaf life-span (P < .001, r2 = 0.72) and increased with A(mass)(P < .001, r2 = 0.78). It appears that a suite of traits including short leaf life-span and high leaf N(mass), SLA, LAR, and A(mass) interactively contribute to high growth rates in open-grown individuals.These traits interact similarly at the stand level, but stands differ from individuals in one key trait. In closed-canopy forests, species with longer lived foliage (and low LAR as seedlings) have greater foliage mass per unit ground area (P < .001, r2 = 0.74) and a greater proportion of total mass in foliage. The aboveground production efficiency (ANPP/foliar biomass) of forest stands decreased markedly with increasing leaf life-span or total foliage mass (P < .001, r2 = 0.78 and 0.72, respectively), probably as a result of decreasing A(mass), N(mass), and SLA, all of which were positively related with production efficiency and negatively related to total foliage mass. However, high foliage mass of species with extended leaflife-spans appears to compensate for low production per unit foliage, since aboveground net primary production (ANPP, in megagrams per hectare per year) of forest stands was not related to leaf life-span. Extended leaf life-span also appears to compensate for lower potential production per unit leaf N per unit time, with the result that stand-level N use efficiency is weakly positively related to leaf life-span.We hypothesize that co-variation among species in leaf life-span, SLA, leaf N(mass), A(mass), and growth rate reflects a set of mutually supporting traits that interact to determine plant behavior and production, and provide a useful conceptual link between processes at short-term leaf scales and longer term whole plant and stand-level scales. Although this paper has focused on leaf-span, this trait is so closely interrelated with several others that this cohort of leaf traits should be viewed as causally interrelated. Generality in the relationships between leaf life-span and other plant traits across diverse communities and ecosystems suggests that they are universal in nature and thus can provide a quantitative link and/or common currency for ecological comparisons among diverse systems.									807	62	763	7	900	0012-9615		WOS:A1992JJ41600003		