PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Lasky, Jesse R.; Sun, I-Fang; Su, Sheng-Hsin; Chen, Zueng-Sang; Keitt, Timothy H.								Trait-mediated effects of environmental filtering on tree community dynamics								JOURNAL OF ECOLOGY				101	3			722	733		10.1111/1365-2745.12065			MAY 2013	2013	Individual performance is a function of an individual's traits and its environment. This function, known as an environmental filter, varies in space and affects community composition. However, filters are poorly characterized because dispersal patterns can obscure environmental effects, and few studies utilize longitudinal data linking individual performance to environment. We model the effects of environmental filters on demographic rates of nearly all tree species (99) in a 25-ha subtropical rain forest plot. We develop a hierarchical Bayesian model of environmental filtering, drawing inspiration from classic studies of intraspecific natural selection. We characterize the specific environmental gradients and trait axes most important in filtering of demographic rates across species. We found that stronger filtering along a given trait axis corresponded to less spatial variation in the value of favoured traits. Environmental gradients associated with filtering were different for growth versus survivorship. Species maximum height was under the strongest filtering for growth, with shorter species favoured on convex ridges. Shorter stature species may be favoured on ridges because trees on ridges experience higher wind damage and lower soil moisture. Wood density filtering had the strongest effects on survival. Steep slopes and high available P in the soil favoured species with low-density wood. Such sites may be favourable for fast-growing species that exploit resource-rich environments. Synthesis: We characterized trait-mediated environmental filters that may underlie spatial niche differentiation and life-history trade-offs, which can promote species coexistence. Filtering along trait axes with the strongest effects on local community composition, that is, traits with the strongest filtering, may necessarily have a weaker potential to promote species coexistence across the plot. The weak spatial variation in filters with strong effects on demography may result from long-term processes affecting the species pool that favour habitat generalist strategies.									7	0	6	0	7	0022-0477		WOS:000318186800018		J	Mendez-Alonzo, Rodrigo; Hernandez-Trejo, Humberto; Lopez-Portillo, Jorge				Lopez Portillo, Jorge/L-2492-2014	Lopez Portillo, Jorge/0000-0002-6827-3297			Salinity constrains size inequality and allometry in two contrasting mangrove habitats in the Gulf of Mexico					2			JOURNAL OF TROPICAL ECOLOGY				28				171	179		10.1017/S0266467412000016			MAR 2012	2012	The competition for resources increases size inequality in trees, particularly under low abiotic stress. Because mangrove communities are subject to site-specific salinity (and therefore abiotic stress) gradients, these habitats should differ in height-diameter allometry and size inequality. The size inequality (by the Gini Coefficient, G) and maximum potential height (Hmax from a height-diameter asymptotic model) were determined within the mangrove forest of a coastal lagoon in Veracruz, Mexico in 20 0.25-ha plots, 10 in interdistributary basins (IBs, lower salinity) having Avicennia germinans, Laguncularia racemosa and Rhizophora mangle and 10 in mudflats (MFs, higher salinity) dominated by A. germinans. Size inequality was significantly higher in IBs (G = 0.59+/-0.02 vs. 0.39+/-0.03). Due to their significant intercorrelation G, total basal area and density were synthesized in one PCA axis accounting for 67% of total variance and inversely correlated with salinity (R = -0.65, P = 0.003). The height-diameter scaling model reached a stable asymptote (H-max range: 16-21 m; coefficient of variation CV: 7.7) in IBs, suggesting that trees can still increase their diameter after achieving maximum height. In MFs, no stable asymptote was reached (Hmax range: 11-26 m; CV: 32.5), suggesting a lower growth rate of diameter in the MF trees when compared with IB trees.									3	0	2	0	3	0266-4674		WOS:000300257300005		J	Ramirez, David A.; Balaguer, Luis; Mancilla, Rosa; Gonzalez, Virginia; Coaguila, Daniel; Talavera, Carmelo; Villegas, Luis; Ortega, Aldo; Jimenez, Percy; Moreno, Jose M.								Leaf-trait responses to irrigation of the endemic fog-oasis tree Myrcianthes ferreyrae: can a fog specialist benefit from regular watering?								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				32	1			65	73		10.1093/treephys/tpr121			JAN 2012	2012	Myrcianthes ferreyrae is an endemic, endangered species, with a small number of individuals located only in hyperarid, fog-oases known as lomas along the Peruvian desert in southern Peru, where fog is the main source of water. Following centuries of severe deforestation, reforestation with this native species was conducted in the Atiquipa lomas, Arequipa-Peru. On five slopes, five 2-year-old seedlings were irrigated monthly with water trapped by raschel-mesh fog collectors, supplementing natural rainfall with 0, 20, 40, 60 and 80 mm month(-1) from February to August 2008. We measured plant growth, increment in basal diameter, height and five leaf traits: leaf mass area (LMA), leaf carbon isotope composition (delta(13)C), nitrogen per leaf area, total leaf carbon and stomatal density; which are indicative of the physiological changes resulting from increased water supply. Plant growth rates, estimated from the variation of either shoot basal diameter or maximum height, were highly correlated with total biomass. Only LMA and delta(13)C were higher in irrigated than in control plants, but we found no further differences among irrigation treatments. This threshold response suggests an on-off strategy fitted to exploit pulses of fog water, which are always limited in magnitude in comparison with natural rain. The absence of a differential response to increased water supply is in agreement with the low phenotypic plasticity expected in plants from very stressful environments. Our results have practical implications for reforestation projects, since irrigating with 20 mm per month is sufficient to achieve the full growth capacity of this species.									1	0	0	0	1	0829-318X		WOS:000299346500007	22147224	J	Gallagher, Rachael V.; Leishman, Michelle R.; Miller, Joseph T.; Hui, Cang; Richardson, David M.; Suda, Jan; Travnicek, Pavel				Richardson, David/A-1495-2008; Hui, Cang/A-1781-2008; Travnicek, Pavel/G-9028-2012; Miller, Joe/D-2729-2009; Suda, Jan/D-3369-2013; Leishman, Michelle/G-9726-2012	Richardson, David/0000-0001-9574-8297; Hui, Cang/0000-0002-3660-8160; Leishman, Michelle/0000-0003-4830-5797			Invasiveness in introduced Australian acacias: the role of species traits and geneome size								DIVERSITY AND DISTRIBUTIONS				17	5	SI		884	897		10.1111/j.1472-4642.2011.00805.x			SEP 2011	2011	Aim To assess associations between invasiveness, genome size and species traits in Australian Acacia species introduced outside their native range.Location Global.Methods Holoploid genome size was determined by flow cytometry for 92 species in Acacia subgenus Phyllodineae native to Australia. These data were used to test whether genome size was significantly different for invasive (n = 21; species known to be established and spreading in foreign environments) and non-invasive (n = 71; species that have been introduced to foreign environments but which are not known to be spreading) species. Data for five functional traits [seed mass, specific leaf area (SLA), relative growth rate (RGR), maximum height and dispersal mode] and three characteristics of native range (size, temperature range and precipitation range) were used to test for univariate and multivariate relationships between (1) invasiveness and traits and (2) genome size and traits.Results Genome size ranged from 1.20 to 2.13 pg/2C and was not significantly smaller in invasive compared with non-invasive acacias. However, invasive acacias were found to be taller and possess a larger native range size and a wider range of annual precipitation when compared with non-invasive acacias. Multivariate analyses revealed significant differences between invasive and non-invasive acacias (PERMANOVA; P < 0.01) driven largely by differences in native range characteristics. We detected a positive relationship between genome size and SLA (P = 0.02) and elaiosome dispersal mode (P < 0.01) in analyses across species, but these findings were not supported by evolutionary divergence analyses.Main conclusions Genome size variation does not underpin variation in traits associated with the invasive/non-invasive dichotomy in introduced acacias, probably because of the very small DNA values in the Acacia species studied. Acacias introduced into new environments are most likely to become invasive if they are tall shrubs or trees and are widely distributed in their native range.									18	0	18	0	18	1366-9516		WOS:000294655400009		J	Osada, Noriyuki				Osada, Noriyuki/K-2946-2012				Height-dependent changes in shoot structure and tree allometry in relation to maximum height in four deciduous tree species								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				25	4			777	786		10.1111/j.1365-2435.2011.01833.x			AUG 2011	2011	1. Tree allometry often varies among coexisting species of different maximum height (H(max)) in forests. Although shoot growth patterns directly influence overall tree architecture, the structures of current-year shoots at the tops of crowns have not been directly related to differences in tree allometry across species.2. I investigated height-dependent changes in structure and biomass allocation patterns in current-year shoots of four coexisting tree species differing in H(max) in a cool-temperate forest in Japan. The relative importance of total biomass, biomass allocation, shoot allometry, and shoot angle to vertical growth was quantified and compared with tree allometry.3. Height-dependent changes in total biomass of current-year shoots varied across species. In contrast, stem length per unit mass, shoot angle, and total leaf area per unit stem cross-sectional area decreased, and leaf mass per unit area increased with height in all species. Vertical growth rate consequently declined with increasing height in all species. Sensitivity analyses revealed that the primary determinant of declining vertical growth rate was change in stem length per unit mass; shoot angle was a secondary determinant. In contrast, increases in total shoot mass with height modulated declining vertical growth rates.4. Vertical growth rate was greater in two canopy species than in two sub-canopy species at given heights at the shoot level, and this pattern coincided with allometry between tree height and trunk diameter. In contrast, vertical growth rate was greater in sub-canopy species than in canopy species near their maximum heights. These patterns suggest that allometric differences between species may be useful for evaluating crown-development patterns, but not for estimating H(max) of species.									4	0	4	0	4	0269-8463		WOS:000292330000006		J	Ambrose, Anthony R.; Sillett, Stephen C.; Koch, George W.; Van Pelt, Robert; Antoine, Marie E.; Dawson, Todd E.								Effects of height on treetop transpiration and stomatal conductance in coast redwood (Sequoia sempervirens)								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				30	10			1260	1272		10.1093/treephys/tpq064			OCT 2010	2010	Treetops become increasingly constrained by gravity-induced water stress as they approach maximum height. Here we examine the effects of height on seasonal and diurnal sap flow dynamics at the tops of 12 unsuppressed Sequoia sempervirens (D. Don) Endl. (coast redwood) trees 68-113 m tall during one growing season. Average treetop sap velocity (V(S)), transpiration per unit leaf area (E(L)) and stomatal conductance per unit leaf area (G(S)) significantly decreased with increasing height. These differences in sap flow were associated with an unexpected decrease in treetop sapwood area-to-leaf area ratios (A(S):A(L)) in the tallest trees. Both E(L) and G(S) declined as soil moisture decreased and vapor pressure deficit (D) increased throughout the growing season with a greater decline in shorter trees. Under high soil moisture and light conditions, reference G(S) (G(Sref); G(S) at D = 1 kPa) and sensitivity of G(S) to D (-delta; dG(S)/dlnD) significantly decreased with increasing height. The close relationship we observed between G(Sref) and -delta is consistent with the role of stomata in regulating E(L) and leaf water potential (Psi(L)). Our results confirm that increasing tree height reduces gas exchange of treetop foliage and thereby contributes to lower carbon assimilation and height growth rates as S. sempervirens approaches maximum height.									15	0	13	0	15	0829-318X		WOS:000282818100003	20631010	J	Herault, Bruno; Ouallet, Julia; Blanc, Lilian; Wagner, Fabien; Baraloto, Christopher				Herault, Bruno/B-2524-2008; Herault, Bruno/B-2765-2011; Wagner, Fabien/B-8364-2013	Herault, Bruno/0000-0002-6950-7286; 			Growth responses of neotropical trees to logging gaps								JOURNAL OF APPLIED ECOLOGY				47	4			821	831		10.1111/j.1365-2664.2010.01826.x			AUG 2010	2010	P>1. Modelling growth strategies among tropical trees is an important objective in predicting the response of tree dynamics to selective logging and in gaining insights into the ecological processes that structure tree communities in managed tropical forests.2. We developed a disturbance index to model the effects of distance to and area of logging gaps on stem radial growth rates. This index was tested using census data of 43 neotropical tree species, representing a variety of life-history strategies and developmental stages, from a selectively logged forest at Paracou, French Guiana. Growth strategies were analyzed in light of two indicators: the inherent species growth rate (when disturbance index is null) and the species reaction (change in growth rate) to logging gaps.3. Across species, the predicted inherent growth rates in unlogged forest ranged from 0 center dot 25 to 6 center dot 47 mm year-1, with an average growth of 2 center dot 29 mm year-1. Ontogenetic shifts in inherent growth rate were found in 26 of the 43 species.4. Species growth response to logging gaps varied widely among species but was significantly positive for 27 species. The effect of ontogeny on growth response to logging was retained for 14 species, and species with inherent fast growth rate (5 mm year-1) responded less to logging gap disturbances than did species with slow inherent growth (1 mm year-1).5. Functional traits explained 19-42% of the variation in the inherent growth rate and in species' response across all developmental stages. Whereas maximum diameters and seed mass were strong predictors of inherent growth rate, maximum height, wood density, mode of germination and stem architecture were additionally involved in tree growth response.6. Synthesis and applications: This study provides a necessary framework for developing predictive post-logging growth models for the thousands of species comprising tropical forests and is sufficiently general to apply to a broad range of managed tropical forests.									14	0	14	0	14	0021-8901		WOS:000279405100012		J	Russo, Sabrina E.; Jenkins, Kerry L.; Wiser, Susan K.; Uriarte, Maria; Duncan, Richard P.; Coomes, David A.				wiser, susan/G-1975-2011; Coomes, David/H-5630-2011; Duncan, Richard/E-7899-2013; Uriarte, Maria/L-8944-2013	Duncan, Richard/0000-0003-2295-449X; 			Interspecific relationships among growth, mortality and xylem traits of woody species from New Zealand								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				24	2			253	262		10.1111/j.1365-2435.2009.01670.x			APR 2010	2010	P>1. Wood density is considered a key functional trait influencing the growth and survival of woody plants and has been shown to be related to a slow-fast rate-of-living continuum. Wood density is, however, an emergent trait arising from several vascular properties of wood, including the diameter and frequency of xylem conduits.2. We aimed to test the hypotheses that there is a set of inter-related trade-offs linked to the different functions of wood, that these trade-offs have direct consequences for tree growth and survival and that these trade-offs underlie the observed correlations between wood density and demographic rates. We evaluated the covariation between xylem anatomical traits among woody species of New Zealand and whether that covariation had the potential to constrain variation in wood density and demographic rates.3. Several xylem traits were strongly correlated with each other, but wood density was not correlated with any of them. We also found no significant relationships between wood density and growth or mortality rate. Instead, growth was strongly related to xylem traits associated with hydraulic capacity (conduit diameter and a conductivity index) and to maximum height, whereas mortality rate was strongly correlated only with maximum height. The diameter and frequency of conduits exhibited a significant negative relationship, suggesting a trade-off, which restricted variation in wood density and growth rate, but not mortality rate.4. Our results suggest, for woody species in New Zealand, that growth rate is more closely linked to xylem traits determining hydraulic conductance, rather than wood density. We also found no evidence that denser woods conferred higher survival, or that risk of cavitation caused by wide conduits increased mortality.5. In summary, we found little support for the idea that wood density is a good proxy for position along a fast-slow rate-of-living continuum. Instead, the strong, negative relationship between vessel diameter and frequency may constrain the realized diversity of demographic niches of tree species in New Zealand. Trade-offs in function therefore have the potential to shape functional diversity and ecology of forest communities by linking selection on structure and function to population-level dynamics.									28	0	27	0	29	0269-8463		WOS:000274952600002		J	Nabeshima, Eri; Kubo, Takuya; Hiura, Tsutom				Kubo, Takuya/A-3414-2012	Kubo, Takuya/0000-0001-6202-9624			Variation in tree diameter growth in response to the weather conditions and tree size in deciduous broad-leaved trees								FOREST ECOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT				259	6			1055	1066		10.1016/j.foreco.2009.12.012			MAR 1 2010	2010	The diameter growth of trees may vary depending on the tree size, species and other tree-related factors. However, such variation is challenging to consider while estimating the growth response to weather conditions. This study investigated the effects of the weather conditions and variations in tree factors on diameter growth in a mature forest. In particular, we focused on diameter growth in June, the month of active diameter growth. We recorded the monthly diameter growth of 6 tree species for 7 years and constructed a generalized linear mixed model in which the mean growth was dependant on tree size, weather conditions, and the interaction between tree size and weather.The estimated growth responses to weather factors were different among species. but their interaction to tree size was unclear in all species. Sensitivity analysis of growth rate to weather conditions, such as temperature and precipitation, showed that the sensitivity to weather depended both on tree size and tree species. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									4	1	3	0	5	0378-1127		WOS:000275313700001		J	Milios, Elias; Smiris, Paulos; Pipinis, Elias; Petrou, Petros								The growth ecology of Juniperus excelsa Bieb. trees in the central part of the Nestos valley (NE Greece) in the context of anthropogenic disturbances								JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH-THESSALONIKI				11				83	94					2009	2009	In order to analyse the growth of Juniperus excelsa Bieb. trees in the stands found in the slopes of Nestos valley, 48 trees growing under different shade and site conditions were studied. Stem analysis was conducted on all trees. The main results of this research indicate that the disturbance regime, shade and site conditions strongly affected the growth of J. excelsa trees. Juniperus excelsa is a species with significant growth plasticity, which is capable of surviving and growing under various competition and disturbance regimes. It is also capable of exhibiting the maximum height growth rate at various ages. Moreover, it has the ability to attain significant ring width growth increases at an old age. Regardless of the fact that J. excelsa behaves as a shade tolerant species which can endure shade for many decades, it is not necessarily a shade demanding species since it can germinate and grow under full light. It seems that the species growth plasticity contributes efficiently to its maintenance in intensely disturbed and severe environments.									4	0	2	0	4	1790-045X		WOS:000268388400009		