PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Hoeber, Stefanie; Leuschner, Christoph; Koehler, Lars; Arias-Aguilar, Dagoberto; Schuldt, Bernhard								The importance of hydraulic conductivity and wood density to growth performance in eight tree species from a tropical semi-dry climate								FOREST ECOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT				330				126	136		10.1016/j.foreco.2014.06.039			OCT 15 2014	2014	Understanding how tropical trees coordinate fast growth with water consumption and carbon investment is of high relevance because climate warming may expose tropical forests to increasing stress. Thus, foresters require more information of native tree species envisaged for reforestation. This study examines the relationship between productivity and possibly growth-determining functional traits of xylem anatomy, hydraulic conductivity, foliar morphology and nutrient status in eight tree species in semi-dry Costa Rica; we further assessed the indicative value of wood density for growth rate and hydraulic efficiency. We tested the hypotheses that (i) wood density is related to both growth rate and hydraulic efficiency contrary to findings from moist tropical forests, and (ii) productivity is closely related to branch xylem properties as well as empirically determined hydraulic conductivity in these drought-adapted species. Growth rate was positively related to tree size, foliar nitrogen content, vessel diameter, specific conductivity and leaf water potential, and negatively to vessel density, wood density and delta C-13, indicating that fast-growing tree species with light wood possessed a more efficient hydraulic system but closed their stomata relatively early to prevent xylem dysfunction. We conclude, that in tropical semi-dry climates, productivity is closely associated not only with foliar nitrogen but also with wood anatomical and hydraulic properties. Wood density proved to be a reliable indicator for growth-related, wood anatomical and hydraulic traits in these drought-adapted species. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									0	0	0	0	0	0378-1127		WOS:000342244500014		J	Fan, Ze-Xin; Zhang, Shi-Bao; Hao, Guang-You; Slik, J. W. Ferry; Cao, Kun-Fang				Cao, Kun-Fang/D-2157-2009	Cao, Kun-Fang/0000-0002-0423-4985			Hydraulic conductivity traits predict growth rates and adult stature of 40 Asian tropical tree species better than wood density								JOURNAL OF ECOLOGY				100	3			732	741		10.1111/j.1365-2745.2011.01939.x			MAY 2012	2012	1. Stem xylem characteristics have a great impact on growth and adult stature of trees because of their role in mechanical support, long-distance water transport and whole-plant carbon allocation. Yet, despite the potential causal link between xylem traits and plant growth/adult stature, most studies have tried to link wood density, an indirect but easy to measure proxy for wood properties, to tree growth and size.2. To determine whether xylem traits outperform wood density as predictors of tree growth and stature, we evaluated the covariation among wood density, xylem anatomical traits, tree diameter growth rate and adult stature in 40 Asian tropical tree species through principal component analyses and through bivariate correlation, both across species and across phylogenetically independent contrasts.3. Vessel diameter exhibited a tight negative relationship with vessel frequency. Wood density showed a significant correlation with vessel diameter and density, but not with vessel fraction. Most correlations between functional traits indicate adaptive coordination, demonstrated by significant correlations between phylogenetically independent contrasts.4. Across species, diameter growth rate and adult stature were positively correlated with vessel lumen diameter and potential hydraulic conductivity, but not with wood density. Thus, our results suggest that xylem anatomical traits that are linked to hydraulic conductivity are better predictors of tree growth rate and adult stature than wood density.5. Synthesis. We found that xylem anatomical traits have a more significant influence on whole-plant performance due to their direct association with stem hydraulic conductivity, whereas wood density is decoupled from hydraulic function due to complex variations in xylem components.									17	3	19	1	21	0022-0477		WOS:000302623200015		J	Beelaerts, Veerle; Bauwens, Maite; Versteegh, Emma; Dehairs, Frank; Pintelon, Rik				Versteegh, Emma/A-5637-2011; Versteegh, Emma/M-3284-2013	Versteegh, Emma/0000-0003-1231-6718; Versteegh, Emma/0000-0003-1231-6718			Periodic Time-Series Modeling of Environmental Proxy Records with Guaranteed Positive Growth Rate Estimation								MATHEMATICAL GEOSCIENCES				43	6			635	662		10.1007/s11004-011-9352-7			AUG 2011	2011	Identifying a periodic time-series model from environmental records, without imposing the positivity of the growth rate, does not necessarily respect the time order of the data observations. Consequently, subsequent observations, sampled in the environmental archive, can be inversed on the time axis, resulting in a non-physical signal model. In this paper an optimization technique with linear constraints on the signal model parameters is proposed that prevents time inversions. The activation conditions for this constrained optimization are based upon the physical constraint of the growth rate, namely, that it cannot take values smaller than zero. The actual constraints are defined for polynomials and first-order splines as basis functions for the nonlinear contribution in the distance-time relationship. The method is compared with an existing method that eliminates the time inversions, and its noise sensitivity is tested by means of Monte Carlo simulations. Finally, the usefulness of the method is demonstrated on the measurements of the vessel density, in a mangrove tree, Rhizophora mucronata, and the measurement of Mg/Ca ratios, in a bivalve, Mytilus trossulus.									0	0	0	0	0	1874-8961		WOS:000293473100003		J	Poorter, Lourens; McDonald, Imole; Alarcon, Alfredo; Fichtler, Esther; Licona, Juan-Carlos; Pena-Claros, Marielos; Sterck, Frank; Villegas, Zulma; Sass-Klaassen, Ute								The importance of wood traits and hydraulic conductance for the performance and life history strategies of 42 rainforest tree species								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				185	2			481	492		10.1111/j.1469-8137.2009.03092.x			2010	2010	P>In a comparative study of 42 rainforest tree species we examined relationships amongst wood traits, diameter growth and survival of large trees in the field, and shade tolerance and adult stature of the species.The species show two orthogonal axes of trait variation: a primary axis related to the vessel size-number trade-off (reflecting investment in hydraulic conductance vs hydraulic safety) and a secondary axis related to investment in parenchyma vs fibres (storage vs strength). Across species, growth rate was positively related to vessel diameter and potential specific hydraulic conductance (K(p)), and negatively related to wood density. Survival rate was only positively related to wood density.Light-demanding species were characterized by low wood and vessel density and wide vessels. Tall species were characterized by wide vessels with low density and large K(p). Hydraulic traits were more closely associated with adult stature than with light demand, possibly because tall canopy species experience more drought stress and face a higher cavitation risk.Vessel traits affect growth and wood density affects growth and survival of large trees in the field. Vessel traits and wood density are therefore important components of the performance and life history strategies of tropical tree species.									93	2	92	1	96	0028-646X		WOS:000272893800013	19925555	J	Sellin, Arne; Rohejaerv, Andrus; Rahi, Maert								Distribution of vessel size, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown of silver birch (Betula pendula)								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				22	2			205	216		10.1007/s00468-007-0177-4			APR 2008	2008	Spatial patterns in vessel diameter, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown were examined in closed-canopy trees of silver birch (Betula pendula). The variation in anatomical and hydraulic characteristics of branches was considered from three perspectives: vertically within a crown (lower, middle and upper crown), radially along main branches (proximal, middle and distal part), and with respect to branch orders (first-, second- and third-order branches). Hydraulically weighted mean diameter of vessels (D (h)) and theoretical specific conductivity of the xylem (k (t)) exhibited no vertical trend within the tree crown, whereas leaf-specific conductivity of the xylem (LSCt) decreased acropetally. Variation in LSCt was governed by sapwood area to leaf area ratio (Huber value) rather than by changes in xylem anatomy. The acropetal increase in soil-to-leaf conductance (G (T)) within the birch canopy is attributable to longer path length within the lower-crown branches and higher hydraulic resistance of the shade leaves. D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, while vessel density (VD) and relative area of vessel lumina (VA) increased distally along main branches. A strong negative relationship between vessel diameter and VD implies a trade-off between hydraulic efficiency and mechanical stability of xylem. D (h) and VD combined explained 85.4% of the total variation of k (t) in the regression model applied to the whole data set. Xylem in fast-growing branches (primary branches) had greater area of vessel lumina per unit cross-sectional area of sapwood, resulting in a positive relationship between branch radial growth rate and k (t). D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, whereas VD increased with increasing branch order. This pattern promotes the hydraulic dominance of primary branches over the secondary branches and their dominance over tertiary branches. In this way crown architecture contributes to preferential water flow along the main axes, potentially providing better water supply for the branch apical bud and foliage located in the outer, better-insolated part of the crown.									14	1	12	0	15	0931-1890		WOS:000254240300009		J	Schmitz, Nele; Verheyden, Anouk; Beeckman, Hans; Gitundu Kairo, James; Koedam, Nico								Influence of a salinity gradient on the vessel characters of the mangrove species Rhizophora mucronata								ANNALS OF BOTANY				98	6			1321	1330		10.1093/aob/mcl224			DEC 2006	2006	Background and Aims Although mangroves have been extensively studied, little is known about their ecological wood anatomy. This investigation examined the potential use of vessel density as a proxy for soil water salinity in the mangrove species Rhizophora mucronata (Rhizophoraceae) from Kenya.Methods In a time-standardized approach, 50 wood discs from trees growing in six salinity categories were investigated. Vessel densities, and tangential and radial diameters of rainy and dry season wood of one distinct year, at three positions on the stem discs, were measured. A repeated-measures ANOVA with the prevailing salinity was performed.Key Results Vessel density showed a significant increase with salinity, supporting its use as a prospective measure of salinity. Interestingly, the negative salinity response of the radial diameter of vessels was less striking, and tangential diameter was constant under the varying environmental conditions. An effect of age or growth rate or the presence of vessel dimorphism could be excluded as the cause of the absence of any ecological trend.Conclusions The clear trend in vessel density with salinity, together with the absence of a growth rate and age effect, validates the potential of vessel density as an environmental proxy. However, it can only be used as a relative measure of salinity given that other environmental variables such as inundation frequency have an additional influence on vessel density. With view to a reliable, absolute proxy, future research should focus on finding wood anatomical features correlated exclusively with soil water salinity or inundation frequency. The plasticity in vessel density with differing salinity suggests a role in the establishment of a safe water transport system. To confirm this hypothesis, the role of inter-vessel pits, their relationship to the rather constant vessel diameter and the underlying physiology and cell biology needs to be examined.									20	0	20	0	21	0305-7364		WOS:000242245400021	17062590	J	De Ridder, F.; Pintelon, R.; Schoukens, J.; Verheyden, A.				Piuri, Vincenzo/A-3970-2012		Demidenko, S.; Ottoboni, R.; Petri, D.; Piuri, V.; Chong, D.; Weng, T.		Reduction of the Gibbs phenomenon in the special case of non-harmonic time base distortions					Vol.1			Proceedings of the 21st IEEE Instrumentation and Measurement Technology Conference (IEEE Cat. No.04CH37510)								318	21 vol.1		10.1109/IMTC.2004.1351053			2004	2004	This paper presents a sine wave fitting procedure for characterizing measurements of a harmonic signal in the presence of additive noise and an unknown time base distortion. In general the reconstructed time base distortion of the existing solutions (Verspecht, 1994; Schoukens et al., 1997) suffers from the Gibbs phenomenon (ringing) at the borders of the data record. Ignoring data samples at the borders is unacceptable for very short data records where measuring a sample is (very) expensive and/or (very) time consuming. This paper presents a solution that suppresses the Gibbs phenomenon in the estimated time base distortion without ignoring data samples at the borders. The theory is illustrated on simulations and on real measurements of the vessel density of a mangrove tree from Kenya (Rhizophora mucronata).					Proceedings of the 21st IEEE Instrumentation and Measurement Technology Conference	18-20 May 2004	IEEE Instrumentation and Measurement Soc	Como, Italy	0	0	0	0	0			INSPEC:8109674		