PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Lusk, Christopher H.; Kaneko, Teruko; Grierson, Ella; Clearwater, Michael								Correlates of tree species sorting along a temperature gradient in New Zealand rain forests: seedling functional traits, growth and shade tolerance								JOURNAL OF ECOLOGY				101	6			1531	1541		10.1111/1365-2745.12152			NOV 2013	2013	It is widely believed that species sorting on environmental gradients reflects trade-offs between competitive ability and physiological tolerance of stresses such as frost and desiccation. One specific expression of this general idea is the hypothesis that tree species sorting on temperature gradients in temperate regions involves a trade-off between growth rate and frost resistance, because adaptations to frost reduce light interception and carbon gain potential. We measured seedling growth of 17 New Zealand rain forest angiosperm trees in a glasshouse, as well as biomass partitioning, gas exchange and hydraulic traits. We then related these variables to the mean July (winter) minimum temperatures most frequently experienced throughout the range of each species. Species associated with mild winters on average had wider vessels and more conductive stems and were leafier (i.e. developed more foliage area per unit sapwood area) than species from frostier sites. Species' positions on the temperature gradient were not significantly correlated with relative growth rates of seedlings; they were, however, negatively correlated with two measures of species light requirements in the field: the light compensation point for growth, and low-light mortality rates obtained from the literature.Synthesis. Although seedling growth rates of warm- and cool-temperate New Zealand angiosperm trees were similar on average, the former are more shade tolerant. Competitive hierarchies associated with tree species sorting on temperature gradients thus probably involve a shift in the relationship between shade tolerance and growth rate, rather than a simple trade-off of growth with cold tolerance. This shift is associated with variation in light interception potential per unit of seedling biomass, possibly reflecting a trade-off between stem conductivity and resistance to freeze-thaw embolism.									1	0	1	0	1	0022-0477		WOS:000325984300016		J	Sellin, Arne; Tullus, Arvo; Niglas, Aigar; Ounapuu, Eele; Karusion, Annika; Lohmus, Krista								Humidity-driven changes in growth rate, photosynthetic capacity, hydraulic properties and other functional traits in silver birch (Betula pendula)								ECOLOGICAL RESEARCH				28	3			523	535		10.1007/s11284-013-1041-1			MAY 2013	2013	A study was performed on saplings of silver birch (Betula pendula Roth) growing at the free air humidity manipulation site, which was established to investigate the effect of increased air humidity on tree performance and canopy functioning. The aim of the experiment was to simulate the impact of the increasing atmospheric humidity on forest ecosystems predicted for northern Europe. Artificially elevated relative humidity (RH), which causes transpirational flux to decrease, diminished nutrient supply to the foliage; leaf nitrogen content, phosphorus content and P:N ratio decreased. The changes in leaf nutritional status brought about a considerable decline in both photosynthetic capacity (A (max), V (cmax), J (max)) and tree growth rate. The manipulation induced diverse changes in tree hydraulic architecture and other functional traits. Different segments of the soil-to-leaf water transport pathway responded differently: leaf hydraulic conductance (K (L)) decreased, while hydraulic conductance of root systems (K (R)) and leaf-specific conductivity of stem-wood increased in response to elevated RH. Humidification caused the Huber values of stems to increase, thus reflecting changes in allocation patterns; relatively more resources were allocated to vascular tissue and less to foliage. The elevated RH induced substantial changes in specific leaf area (increased), branch- (decreased) and stem-wood density (decreased). The observed responses suggest that the expected climate-change-induced increase in the growth rate of trees at northern latitudes (boreal areas) due to the earlier start of the growing season in spring or higher carbon assimilation rate could be smaller or null if temperature rise is accompanied by a rise in atmospheric absolute humidity.									7	0	6	0	7	0912-3814		WOS:000318569100016		J	Sellin, Arne; Rohejaerv, Andrus; Rahi, Maert								Distribution of vessel size, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown of silver birch (Betula pendula)								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				22	2			205	216		10.1007/s00468-007-0177-4			APR 2008	2008	Spatial patterns in vessel diameter, vessel density and xylem conducting efficiency within a crown were examined in closed-canopy trees of silver birch (Betula pendula). The variation in anatomical and hydraulic characteristics of branches was considered from three perspectives: vertically within a crown (lower, middle and upper crown), radially along main branches (proximal, middle and distal part), and with respect to branch orders (first-, second- and third-order branches). Hydraulically weighted mean diameter of vessels (D (h)) and theoretical specific conductivity of the xylem (k (t)) exhibited no vertical trend within the tree crown, whereas leaf-specific conductivity of the xylem (LSCt) decreased acropetally. Variation in LSCt was governed by sapwood area to leaf area ratio (Huber value) rather than by changes in xylem anatomy. The acropetal increase in soil-to-leaf conductance (G (T)) within the birch canopy is attributable to longer path length within the lower-crown branches and higher hydraulic resistance of the shade leaves. D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, while vessel density (VD) and relative area of vessel lumina (VA) increased distally along main branches. A strong negative relationship between vessel diameter and VD implies a trade-off between hydraulic efficiency and mechanical stability of xylem. D (h) and VD combined explained 85.4% of the total variation of k (t) in the regression model applied to the whole data set. Xylem in fast-growing branches (primary branches) had greater area of vessel lumina per unit cross-sectional area of sapwood, resulting in a positive relationship between branch radial growth rate and k (t). D (h), k (t) and LSCt decreased, whereas VD increased with increasing branch order. This pattern promotes the hydraulic dominance of primary branches over the secondary branches and their dominance over tertiary branches. In this way crown architecture contributes to preferential water flow along the main axes, potentially providing better water supply for the branch apical bud and foliage located in the outer, better-insolated part of the crown.									14	1	12	0	15	0931-1890		WOS:000254240300009		J	Woodrum, CL; Ewers, FW; Telewski, FW								Hydraulic, biomechanical, and anatomical interactions of xylem from five species of Acer (Aceraceae)								AMERICAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY				90	5			693	699		10.3732/ajb.90.5.693			MAY 2003	2003	Possible trade-offs between hydraulic conductivity and mechanical properties of woody stems from five species were assessed. Acer negundo is a ruderal tree, A. saccharinum, and A. rubrum are fast-growing and shade-intolerant soft maples, whereas A. nigrum and A. saccharum are slow-growing and shade-tolerant hard maples. It was hypothesized that the ruderal and soft maples would have lower modulus of elasticity (MOE) and modulus of rupture (MOR), but higher maximum specific conductivity (K-s max) than hard maples. Many anatomical and general morphological characteristics were measured in an attempt to correlate them to water transport and/or mechanical strength differences between species. No difference was found between species in vessel diameter, fiber wall thickness, initial hydraulic conductivity (K-h initial), specific conductivity (K-s max), native percent embolism, or Huber value. Similarly, no trade-off was found between K-s max and MOE or MOR across the genus. However, fiber lumen diameter was inversely correlated to MOE and MOR. Surprisingly, percentage of ray parenchyma was positively related to MOE. The results suggest transport/mechanical trade-offs do not occur in Acer and differences in mechanical properties may be due to fiber lumen differences that do not influence the efficient transport of water.									26	0	27	0	28	0002-9122		WOS:000183133400004	21659164	