PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Iida, Yoshiko; Kohyama, Takashi S.; Swenson, Nathan G.; Su, Sheng-Hsin; Chen, Chien-Teh; Chiang, Jyh-Min; Sun, I-Fang								Linking functional traits and demographic rates in a subtropical tree community: the importance of size dependency								JOURNAL OF ECOLOGY				102	3			641	650		10.1111/1365-2745.12221			MAY 2014	2014	An important goal in plant community ecology is to understand how species traits determine demographic performance. Several functional traits have been shown to correlate with growth and mortality rates in trees, but less is known about how the relationships between functional traits and demographic rates change with tree size.We examined the associations of functional traits with growth and mortality across 43 tree species in the Fushan 25-ha subtropical rain forest plot in northern Taiwan. We estimated the 95th percentile maximum stem diameter, wood density and six leaf functional traits (leaf area, specific leaf area, thickness, succulence, and mass-based nitrogen and phosphorus contents) obtained from leaves on juvenile and adult individuals of each species.To quantify size-dependent changes in growth and mortality, relative growth rate (RGR) and mortality were estimated as a function of stem diameter using hierarchical Bayesian models. These rate estimates were then correlated with functional traits at a range of stem diameter classes.Relationships between functional traits and demographic rates varied with tree size. Maximum size was positively correlated with RGR across a wide range of tree sizes. Wood density was negatively correlated with RGR and mortality for small-sized trees. Leaf traits such as leaf area and specific leaf area at juvenile and adult stages were associated more strongly with demographic rates for corresponding sizes than from other sizes.Synthesis. The observed size-dependent changes in the trait-demography relationships are possibly due to the effects of developmental and environmental changes with increasing tree size. The underlying effects of functional traits on demographic performance vary with tree size, and this should influence dynamics in a tree community.									0	0	0	0	0	0022-0477		WOS:000334588300010		J	Vitasse, Yann; Lenz, Armando; Kollas, Chris; Randin, Christophe F.; Hoch, Guenter; Koerner, Christian				Korner, Christian/B-6592-2014				Genetic vs. non-genetic responses of leaf morphology and growth to elevation in temperate tree species								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				28	1	SI		243	252		10.1111/1365-2435.12161			FEB 2014	2014	1At high elevation, temperate trees generally exhibit adaptive genetic differentiation in their morphological and physiological traits. On account of this directional selection, we hypothesized that tree populations growing near their upper cold elevational limits exhibit lower phenotypic plasticity of growth and leaf morphological traits in response to temperature changes than populations growing at lower elevations.Seedlings of six common deciduous tree species originating from low and high elevations were transplanted into eight common gardens along two elevational gradients in the Swiss Alps. The aim of the experiment was to evaluate the genetic differentiation in growth and leaf morphology between populations from low and high elevations and to quantify the phenotypic plasticity of these traits to temperature changes.In contrast to growth that decreased with increasing elevation, leaf mass per area (LMA) showed no significant change with elevation of common garden, except for a decrease in Laburnum alpinum for both low- and high-elevation provenances. Interestingly, leaf density was found to decrease with elevation of the gardens for all species. Genetic differentiation between low- and high-elevation populations was found in both leaf morphology and growth: high-elevation populations tended to have slower growth rate than low-elevation populations, while no consistent trend was found for LMA across species. Interestingly, for Acer pseudoplatanus and Fraxinus excelsior high-elevation populations exhibited a lower phenotypic plasticity of growth in response to temperature compared to lower populations, whereas no interactions between the elevation of a provenance and the elevation of the garden was detected for the four other species.Hence, during young life stages, the expected increase in tree growth in future warmer climates might be lower in populations living in the coldest part of the species distribution range in temperate species such as Acer pseudoplatanus and Fraxinus excelsior, but similar in other tree species, disregarding other environmental changes.									2	0	2	0	2	0269-8463		WOS:000331083900024		J	Han, Yansha; Wang, Wei; Sun, Jian; Ding, Mingquan; Zhao, Rui; Deng, Shurong; Wang, Feifei; Hu, Yue; Wang, Yang; Lu, Yanjun; Du, Liping; Hu, Zanmin; Diekmann, Heike; Shen, Xin; Polle, Andrea; Chen, Shaoliang								Populus euphratica XTH overexpression enhances salinity tolerance by the development of leaf succulence in transgenic tobacco plants								JOURNAL OF EXPERIMENTAL BOTANY				64	14			4225	4238		10.1093/jxb/ert229			NOV 2013	2013	Populus euphratica is a salt-tolerant tree species that develops leaf succulence after a prolonged period of salinity stress. In the present study, a putative xyloglucan endotransglucosylase/hydrolase gene (PeXTH) from P. euphratica was isolated and transferred to tobacco plants. PeXTH localized exclusively to the endoplasmic reticulum and cell wall. Plants overexpressing PeXTH were more salt tolerant than wild-type tobacco with respect to root and leaf growth, and survival. The increased capacity for salt tolerance was due mainly to the anatomical and physiological alterations caused by PeXTH overexpression. Compared with the wild type, PeXTH-transgenic plants contained 36% higher water content per unit area and 39% higher ratio of fresh weight to dry weight, a hallmark of leaf succulence. However, the increased water storage in the leaves in PeXTH-transgenic plants was not accompanied by greater leaf thickness but was due to highly packed palisade parenchyma cells and fewer intercellular air spaces between mesophyll cells. In addition to the salt dilution effect in response to NaCl, these anatomical changes increased leaf water-retaining capacity, which lowered the increase of salt concentration in the succulent tissues and mesophyll cells. Moreover, the increased number of mesophyll cells reduced the intercellular air space, which improved carbon economy and resulted in a 4778% greater net photosynthesis under control and salt treatments (100150mM NaCl). Taken together, the results indicate that PeXTH overexpression enhanced salt tolerance by the development of succulent leaves in tobacco plants without swelling.									5	0	5	0	5	0022-0957		WOS:000326724700010	24085577	J	Sack, Lawren; Scoffoni, Christine; John, Grace P.; Poorter, Hendrik; Mason, Chase M.; Mendez-Alonzo, Rodrigo; Donovan, Lisa A.								How do leaf veins influence the worldwide leaf economic spectrum? Review and synthesis								JOURNAL OF EXPERIMENTAL BOTANY				64	13			4053	4080		10.1093/jxb/ert316			OCT 2013	2013	Leaf vein traits are implicated in the determination of gas exchange rates and plant performance. These traits are increasingly considered as causal factors affecting the leaf economic spectrum (LES), which includes the light-saturated rate of photosynthesis, dark respiration, foliar nitrogen concentration, leaf dry mass per area (LMA) and leaf longevity. This article reviews the support for two contrasting hypotheses regarding a key vein trait, vein length per unit leaf area (VLA). Recently, Blonder et al. (2011, 2013) proposed that vein traits, including VLA, can be described as the origin of the LES by structurally determining LMA and leaf thickness, and thereby vein traits would predict LES traits according to specific equations. Careful re-examination of leaf anatomy, published datasets, and a newly compiled global database for diverse species did not support the vein origin hypothesis, and moreover showed that the apparent power of those equations to predict LES traits arose from circularity. This review provides a flux trait network hypothesis for the effects of vein traits on the LES and on plant performance, based on a synthesis of the previous literature. According to this hypothesis, VLA, while virtually independent of LMA, strongly influences hydraulic conductance, and thus stomatal conductance and photosynthetic rate. We also review (i) the specific physiological roles of VLA; (ii) the role of leaf major veins in influencing LES traits; and (iii) the role of VLA in determining photosynthetic rate per leaf dry mass and plant relative growth rate. A clear understanding of leaf vein traits provides a new perspective on plant function independently of the LES and can enhance the ability to explain and predict whole plant performance under dynamic conditions, with applications towards breeding improved crop varieties.									6	0	6	0	6	0022-0957		WOS:000325765000012	24123455	J	Villar, Rafael; Ruiz-Robleto, Jeannete; Luis Ubera, Jose; Poorter, Hendrik								EXPLORING VARIATION IN LEAF MASS PER AREA (LMA) FROM LEAF TO CELL: AN ANATOMICAL ANALYSIS OF 26 WOODY SPECIES								AMERICAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY				100	10			1969	1980		10.3732/ajb.1200562			OCT 2013	2013	Premise of the study: Plant species differ widely in the leaf biomass invested per unit area (LMA). LMA can be explained by variation in leaf thickness and/ or density, both of which are infl uenced by anatomical tissue composition. The aim of this study is to quantify the anatomical characteristics that underlie variation in LMA in a range of woody species.Methods: Twenty-six woody species, forming 13 species pairs with a deciduous and evergreen species from the same genus or family, were grown in a glasshouse. The youngest full-grown leaves were analyzed for LMA and morpho-anatomical characteristics at leaf, tissue, and cell level.Key Results: Considered over all species studied, leaf thickness and density were equally important to explain the variation in LMA, but the class difference between deciduous and evergreen species was mainly determined by thickness, whereas variation within each group was largely due to density. Evergreens had thicker leaves, predominantly caused by a larger volume of mesophyll and air spaces, whereas the higher leaf density within each group was due to a lower proportion of epidermis and air spaces, and overall smaller cells.Conclusions: The anatomical basis for variation in LMA in woody species depends on the contrast made. Higher LMA in evergreens is mainly due to a greater leaf thickness, caused by a larger volume of mesophyll and air spaces. Within deciduous species and evergreens, higher LMA is caused by a higher density, due to higher volumetric fractions of mesophyll and lower fractions of air spaces and epidermis.									1	0	0	0	1	0002-9122		WOS:000325712800005	24107583	J	Liu, B. H.; Cheng, L.; Liang, D.; Zou, Y. J.; Ma, F. W.								Growth, gas exchange, water-use efficiency, and carbon isotope composition of 'Gale Gala' apple trees grafted onto 9 wild Chinese rootstocks in response to drought stress								PHOTOSYNTHETICA				50	3			401	410		10.1007/s11099-012-0048-0			SEP 2012	2012	To determine the effects of rootstock choice on the scion response to drought stress, we compared the vegetative growth, biomass accumulation, gas exchange, and water-use efficiency (WUE) of 'Gale Gala' apple (Malus domestica Borkh.) trees grafted onto nine wild Chinese Malus rootstocks. Compared with the well-watered control, drought treatment limited growth, as manifested by smaller increments in plant height (PH), trunk diameter (TD), total fresh biomass (TB), total dry biomass (TDB), total leaf area (LA), and relative growth rate (RGR). The extent of this effect differed among rootstocks. Stress conditions led to increases in the root/shoot ratio (RSR), leaf thickness (LT), water-holding capacity (WHC), carbon isotope composition (delta C-13), and WUE. Decreases were noted in stomatal density (SD), leaf relative water content (RWC), chlorophyll content (Chl), net photosynthetic rate (P (N)), transpiration rate (E), and stomatal conductance (g (s)), again varying by rootstock. Those that are generally considered more drought-tolerant, e.g., M. sieversii, M. prunifolia, and M. toringoides, had smaller declines in PH, TD, TB, TDB, LA, RGR, SD, RWC, Chl, P (N), E, and g (s) and proportionally greater increases in RSR, LT, WHC, delta C-13, and WUE compared with the droughtsensitive M. hupehensis and M. sieboldii. These results suggest that moisture stress has a significant dwarfing effect in the latter two species. Based on WUE calculations, trees on drought-tolerant rootstocks showed higher tolerance when stressed, whereas those on drought-sensitive rootstocks were less tolerant, as indicated by their lower WUE values.									1	0	1	0	1	0300-3604		WOS:000307309000012		J	Gonzalez-Rodriguez, A. M.; Peters, J.								Strategies of leaf expansion in Ficus carica under semiarid conditions								PLANT BIOLOGY				12	3			469	474		10.1111/j.1438-8677.2009.00220.x			MAY 2010	2010	Leaf area expansion, thickness and inclination, gas exchange parameters and relative chlorophyll content were analysed in field-grown fig (Ficus carica L.) leaves over time, from emergence until after full leaf expansion (FLE). Ficus carica leaves showed a subtle change in shape during the early stages of development, and FLE was reached within ca. 30 days after emergence. Changes in leaf thickness and inclination after FLE demonstrated good adaptation to environmental conditions during summer in areas with a Mediterranean climate. Changes in gas exchange parameters and relative chlorophyll content showed that F. carica is a delayed-greening species, reaching maximum values 20 days after FLE. Correlation analysis of datasets collected during leaf expansion, confirmed dependence among structural and functional traits in F. carica. Pn was directly correlated with stomatal conductance (Gs), transpiration (E), leaf area (LA) and relative chlorophyll content up to FLE. The effect of pruning on leaf expansion, a cultural technique commonly applied in this fruit tree, was also evaluated. Although leaf development in pruned branches gave a significantly higher relative leaf area growth rate (RGR(1)) and higher LA than non-pruned branches, no significant differences were found in other morphological and physiological traits, indicating no pruning effect on leaf development. All studied morphological and physiological characteristics indicate that F. carica is well adapted to semiarid conditions. The delayed greening strategy of this species is discussed.									2	1	2	0	3	1435-8603		WOS:000276618400010	20522183	J	King, DJ; Gleadow, RM; Woodrow, IE								Terpene deployment in Eucalyptus polybractea; relationships with leaf structure, environmental stresses, and growth								FUNCTIONAL PLANT BIOLOGY				31	5			451	460		10.1071/FP03217			2004	2004	Terpene deployment was examined in a population of Eucalyptus polybractea ( R. Baker) trees. Eucalyptus polybractea is a terpene-accumulating species, which stores terpenes in oil glands beneath the leaf surface. Using regression analysis, we showed that leaf thickness, measured as leaf mass per area (LMA), influenced terpene content, apparently through regulation of gland dimensions, and thus, gland volume. We also examined how environmental factors affected terpene content through regulation of both LMA, and therefore, storage capacity, and the supply of resources for terpene synthesis. Neither water stress, measured using carbon isotope ratios as an indicator, nor nutrient stress, measured as foliar nitrogen and phosphorus content, accounted for observed variation in either terpene content or LMA. Phenolic content, measured as a possible competing carbon sink, did not account for variation in terpene content, and variation in environmental stresses could not account for differences in growth rate. However, both terpenes and total carbon-based secondary metabolites (terpenes and phenolics) showed positive correlations with growth, suggesting plants gain a growth advantage by deploying greater amounts of secondary metabolites.					1st Meeting of Plant Ecophysiologists (ECOFIZZ)	2003		Univ Melbourne, Sch Bot, Melbourne, AUSTRALIA	23	1	19	1	24	1445-4408		WOS:000221713600007		J	Grotkopp, E; Rejmanek, M; Rost, TL								Toward a causal explanation of plant invasiveness: Seedling growth and life-history strategies of 29 pine (Pinus) species								AMERICAN NATURALIST				159	4			396	419		10.1086/338995			APR 2002	2002	We studied 29 pine (Pinus) species to test the hypothesis that invasive species in disturbed habitats have distinct attributes. Seedling relative growth rate (RGR) and measures of invasiveness were positively associated across species as well as within phylogenetically independent contrasts. High RGR, small seed masses, and short generation times characterize pine species that are successful invaders in disturbed habitats. Discriminant analysis and logistic regression revealed that RGR was the most significant factor among these life-history traits separating invasive and noninvasive species. We also explored the causes of differences in RGR among invasive and noninvasive species. While net assimilation rate, leaf mass ratio, and specific leaf area (SLA) were all found to be contributing positively to RGR, SLA was found to be the main component responsible for differences in RGR between invasive and noninvasive pines. We investigated differences in SLA further by studying leaf anatomy, leaf density, and leaf thickness. We also evaluated relative leaf production rate as an important aspect of SLA. We proposed a hypothetical causal network of all relevant variables.									274	10	260	4	299	0003-0147		WOS:000174252000007	18707424	J	Balok, CA; St Hilaire, R								Drought responses among seven southwestern landscape tree taxa								JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR HORTICULTURAL SCIENCE				127	2			211	218					MAR 2002	2002	Identification of tree taxa that can thrive on reduced moisture regimes mandated by xeriscape programs of the southwest United States could be facilitated if responses to drought of those taxa are determined. Leaf water relations, plant development, and cuticular wax content of seven taxa maintained as well-irrigated controls or exposed to drought and irrigated based on evapotranspiration were studied. Leaf water potential of drought-stressed Fraxinus velutina Torr. (Arizona ash), Koelreuteria paniculata Laxm. (golden rain tree), Quercus macrocarpa Michx. (bur oak), and Quercus muchlenbergii Engelm. (chinkapin oak) were lower at predawn than the controls. Drought-stressed plants of F. velutina, K.paniculata, and Quercus lobata Nee (California white oak) had more negative midday water potential than the control plants. Drought reduced stomatal conductance to as little as 17%, 23%, and 45% of controls in F. velutina, K.paniculata, and Q. macrocarpa, respectively. Drought-stressed plants of F. velutina,K.paniculata, Q. macrocarpa, and Q. muehlenbergii had reduced transpiration rates. Fraxinus velutina had both the highest net assimilation rate (NAR) and relative growth rate (RGR) regardless of irrigation treatment. Mean specific leaf weight (dry weight (DW) of a 1-cm(2) leaf disc divided by the weight), trichome density, stomatal density, leaf thickness, and cuticular wax content varied among species but not between irrigation treatments. Leaves of Q. buckleyi Buckl. (Texas red oak) had one of the highest stomatal densities, and also had leaves which were among the waxiest, most dense, and thickest. Abaxial leaf surfaces of F. velutina were the most pubescent. Across species, drought led to lower ratios of leaf surface area to root DW, and leaf DW to root DW. Quercus buckleyi plants subjected to drought had the highest root to shoot DW ratio (3.1). The low relative growth rate of Q. buckleyi might limit widespread landscape use. However, Q. buckleyi may merit increased use in landscapes on a reduced moisture budget because of foliar traits, carbon allocation patterns, ana the relative lack of impact of drought on plant tissue water relations.									13	0	14	0	17	0003-1062		WOS:000173901200011		J	Veneklaas, EJ; Silva, MPRMS; den Ouden, F				Veneklaas, Erik/C-8907-2009				Determinants of growth rate in Ficus benjamina L. compared to related faster-growing woody and herbaceous species								SCIENTIA HORTICULTURAE				93	1			75	84		10.1016/S0304-4238(01)00315-6			FEB 28 2002	2002	Woody plants are believed to have inherently lower growth rates than herbaceous plants. For economically important species like the ornamental plant Ficus benjamina (Moraceae) it would be advantageous if such a limitation could be partly overcome in order to reduce growing periods. To identify the physiological causes for the low relative growth rate of this species, we compared it with three species of taxonomically related families: Musanga cecropioides (Moraceae), a fast-growing tropical pioneer tree; Cannabis sativa (Cannabaceae), a ruderal herb; and Pilea nummularifolia (Urticaceae), a tropical forest understorey herb. Relative growth rate at similar plant size was about half for F benjamina (65 mg(-1) day(-1)) as compared to the other tree species and the two herbaceous species (113-137 mg(-1) day(-1)), due mainly to differences in leaf area ratio (LAR; 15.9 vs. 25.9-34.1 m(2) kg(-1)). Net assimilation rates were neither different, nor were measured rates of leaf photosynthesis, The differences in LAR were brought about by differences in leaf morphology/anatomy rather than differences in biomass allocation to leaves: specific leaf area (SLA) of F. benjamina was much lower (28.9 vs. 46.6-52.7 m(2) kg(-1)), whereas leaf mass ratio (LMR) was not. Both leaf thickness and dry matter fraction varied among species, but E benjamina was the only species with high values for both variables, and hence had the lowest SLA. The two trees did not show higher investment in woody stems. We conclude that at similar size woody plants do not necessarily have lower growth rates than herbaceous plants. SLA is a key trait determining growth rate, Selection for higher SLA may enhance productivity, but caution is warranted due to likely reductions in leaf life-span and tolerance to abiotic and biotic stress. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.									16	0	15	0	17	0304-4238		WOS:000173795200008		J	Ryser, R; Wahl, S								Interspecific variation in RGR and the underlying traits among 24 grass species grown in full daylight								PLANT BIOLOGY				3	4			426	436					JUL 2001	2001	A growth analysis was conducted with 24 central European grass species in full daylight to test whether traits underlying interspecific variation in relative growth rate (RGR) are the same in full daylight as they are at lower light, and whether this depends on the ecological characteristics of the studied species, i.e., their requirements with respect to nutrient and light availability. In contrast to studies with herbaceous species at lower light, net assimilation rate (NAR) contributed more than leaf area ratio (LAR) or specific leaf area (SLA) to interspecific variation in RGR. This was associated with a larger interspecific variation in NAR than found in experiments with lower light. Without the two most shade-tolerant species, however, the contribution of LAR and its components to interspecific variation in RGR was similar or even higher than that of NAR. Leaf dry matter content correlated negatively with RGR and was the only component of LAR contributing in a similar manner to variation in LAIR and RGR. There was a positive correlation between NAR and biomass allocation to roots, which may be a result of nutrient-limited growth. RGR correlated negatively with biomass allocation to leaves. Leaf thickness did not correlate with RGR, as the positive effect of thin leaves was counterbalanced by their lower NAR. Low inherent RGR was associated with species from nutrient-poor or shady habitats. Different components constrained growth for these two groups of species, those from nutrient-poor habitats having high leaf dry matter content, while those from shady habitats had thin leaves with low NAR.									18	0	17	0	18	1435-8603		WOS:000170738300017		J	Mediavilla, S; Escudero, A; Heilmeier, H								Internal leaf anatomy and photosynthetic resource-use efficiency: interspecific and intraspecific comparisons								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				21	4			251	259					MAR 2001	2001	Leaf mass per unit area (LMA) and internal leaf anatomy often affect net gas exchange because of their effects on internal CO2 conductance to the site of carboxylation, internal shading, competition for CO2 among carboxylation sites, nitrogen concentration and its partitioning. To evaluate effects of LMA and leaf anatomy on CO2 assimilation, water-use efficiency (WUE) and nitrogen-use efficiency (NUE), we measured LMA, leaf thickness, the thickness of mesophyll components, and gas exchange rates at ambient CO2 concentration in leaves of six woody deciduous and evergreen species with different leaf life spans. In two species, CO2 assimilation was also estimated at saturating CO2 concentrations.There were interspecific differences in all morphological variables studied. Long-lived leaves had higher LMA and were thicker than short-lived leaves. Species with high LMA had low assimilation rates and NUE, both in ambient and saturating CO2 concentrations. Thus, in species with high LMA, assimilation was reduced by non-stomatal limitations, possibly because of a lower allocation of N to the photosynthetic machinery than in species with low LMA. Within a species, thicker leaves tended to have a lower tissue density. In intraspecific comparisons under field conditions, increasing internal air volume had positive effects on WUE, probably because of enhanced internal CO2 conductance to the site of carboxylation. We conclude that, in interspecific comparisons, different patterns of N partitioning strongly influence NUE, whereas in intraspecific comparisons, internal leaf anatomy is a key factor regulating resource-use efficiency.									59	2	53	3	62	0829-318X		WOS:000167266700006	11276419	J	Castro-Diez, P; Puyravaud, JP; Cornelissen, JHC								Leaf structure and anatomy as related to leaf mass per area variation in seedlings of a wide range of woody plant species and types								OECOLOGIA				124	4			476	486		10.1007/PL00008873			SEP 2000	2000	The structural causes of variation in leaf mass per area, and of variations in leaf structure accounted for by leaf habit and life form, were explored in a set of laboratory-grown seedlings of 52 European woody species. The leaf traits analysed included density, thickness, saturated mass/dry mass, and leaf nitrogen per mass and per area. Other traits described the anatomy of leaves, most of them relating: to the lamina (proportions of palisade and spongy parenchymata, epidermis, air space and sclerified tissues, expressed as volume per leaf area, and per-cell transversal areas of epidermis and parenchymata), and another referring to the mid rib (transversal section of sclerified tissues). Across the whole set of species leaf mass per area was correlated with leaf density but not with thickness. and this was confirmed by taxonomic relatedness tests. Denser leaves corresponded with greater proportion of sclerified tissues in the lamina, smaller cells and lower water and N contents, but no relation was found with the proportion of air space in the lamina. Taxonomic relatedness analysis statistically supported the negative association of leaf density with saturated to dry leaf mass ratio. Thicker leaves also exhibited greater volume per leaf area and greater individual cell area in each of the tissues, particularly parenchyma. Mean leaf mass per area and leaf thickness were lower in deciduous than in evergreen species, but no significant differences in leaf density, proportion of sclerified tissues in the lamina or cell area were found between the two groups. Leaf mass per area was higher in trees and subshrubs than in shrubs and climbers-plus-scramblers, this rank being equal for leaf density and proportion of sclerified tissues in the lamina, and reversed for cell area. Given the standardised environment and ontogenetic phase of the seedlings, we conclude that variation in leaf structure and anatomy among species and species groups has a strong genetic basis, and is already expressed early in the development of woody plants. From an ecological viewpoint, we can interpret greater leaf mass per area across this species set as greater allocation to support and defence functions, as shown predominantly by species from resource-poor environments.									99	25	93	4	128	0029-8549		WOS:000089509700002		J	Nielsen, SL; Enriquez, S; Duarte, CM; SandJensen, K				Duarte, Carlos M./A-7670-2013				Scaling maximum growth rates across photosynthetic organisms								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				10	2			167	175		10.2307/2389840			APR 1996	1996	1. This study provides evidence for the existence of general intrinsic patterns controlling the maximum growth rate of photosynthetic organisms, based on a compilation of data from more than 120 reports, the species ranging from unicellular algae to trees and thick-leaved desert plants.2. We used thickness and nutrient concentration of the photosynthetic tissue to scale differences in maximum growth rate among plants, based on the demonstrated importance of these plant traits in regulating the maximum growth rates of particular plant groups.3. The growth rate declined with increasing thickness of the photosynthetic structures and increased with increasing nitrogen and phosphorus concentration. The strong dependence of growth rate and nutrient concentrations on tissue thickness reflect broad-scale patterns and not the adaptive response of individual or closely related species of similar tissue thickness to varying environmental conditions.4. The scaling of maximum growth rate is similar to the scaling of metabolic rate to animal size. Thickness of the photosynthetic structures therefore plays an important role in the environmental control of plant performance and evolution, setting thresholds for the growth and productivity of photosynthetic organisms.									64	4	62	0	70	0269-8463		WOS:A1996UV19200002		