PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Brenes-Arguedas, Tania; Roddy, Adam B.; Kursar, Thomas A.				Roddy, Adam/M-4523-2013	Roddy, Adam/0000-0002-4423-8729			Plant traits in relation to the performance and distribution of woody species in wet and dry tropical forest types in Panama								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				27	2			392	402		10.1111/1365-2435.12036			APR 2013	2013	Understanding the factors that limit species distributions along environmental gradients is a central question of ecology. Here, we evaluate the hypothesis that the traits that result in performance trade-offs between habitats contribute to the turnover of woody species along a rainfall gradient in the Isthmus of Panama. We studied 24 plant species with contrasting distributions along this rainfall gradient. We measured 18 morphological and physiological traits, and three performance variables in seedlings planted in common garden experiments in two contrasting sites across the Isthmus. We found evidence for a trade-off suggesting that better survival during the dry season corresponded to a lower growth rate in the forest understorey. This trade-off correlated well with the distribution of the species along the rainfall gradient and was explained mostly by variation in photosynthetic capacity. While not all species fit into this trade-off, most dry-distribution species, which we had previously reported to have higher drought survival, were associated with higher stem hydraulic conductance and higher capacity for CO2 assimilation. Our interpretation is that this combination of traits may be associated mostly with desiccation avoidance (deep roots) or desiccation delay (deciduousness) rather than desiccation tolerance. Despite their higher photosynthetic capacity, these species had lower growth in the low-light understorey, probably because of higher maintenance costs (dark respiration rates). Wet-distribution species, on the other hand, had lower photosynthetic capacity and higher leaf area ratio. This strategy is typical of shade-tolerant species and may explain their higher growth rates in the low-light understorey. In conclusion, our results suggest that habitat associations along the rainfall gradient in the Isthmus of Panama may result in part from a trade-off between traits that are favourable to species that avoid or delay desiccation but that otherwise limit shade tolerance. This trade-off may limit the capacity of some dry-distribution species to colonize wet forests.									1	0	1	0	1	0269-8463		WOS:000317306000012		J	McGhee, Gayle C.; Sundin, George W.								Evaluation of Kasugamycin for Fire Blight Management, Effect on Nontarget Bacteria, and Assessment of Kasugamycin Resistance Potential in Erwinia amylovora								PHYTOPATHOLOGY				101	2			192	204		10.1094/PHYTO-04-10-0128			FEB 2011	2011	The emergence and spread of streptomycin-resistant strains of Erwinia amylovora in Michigan has necessitated the evaluation of new compounds effective for fire blight control. The aminoglycoside antibiotic kasugamycin (Ks) targets the bacterial ribosome and is particularly active against E. amylovora. The efficacy of Ks formulated as Kasumin 2L for control of fire blight was evaluated in six experiments conducted over four field seasons in our experimental orchards in East Lansing, MI. Blossom blight control was statistically equivalent to the industry standard streptomycin in all experiments. E. amylovora populations remained constant on apple flower stigmas pretreated with Kasumin and were approximate to 100-fold lower than on stigmas treated with water. Kasumin applied to apple trees in the field also resulted in a 100-fold reduced total culturable bacterial population compared with trees treated with water. We performed a prospective analysis of the potential for kasugamycin resistance (Ks(R)) development in E. amylovora which focused on spontaneous resistance development and acquisition of a transferrable Ks(R) gene. In replicated lab experiments, the development of spontaneous resistance in E. amylovora to Ks at 250 or 500 ppm was not observed when cells were directly plated on medium containing high concentrations of the antibiotic. However, exposure to increasing concentrations of Ks in media (initial concentration 25 mu g ml(-1)) resulted in the selection of Ks resistance (at 150 mu g ml(-1)) in the E. amylovora strains Ea110, Ea273, and Ea1189. Analysis of mutants indicated that they harbored mutations in the kasugamycin target ksgA gene and that all mutants were impacted in relative fitness observable through a reduced growth rate in vitro and decreased virulence in immature pear fruit. The possible occurrence of a reservoir of Ks(R) genes in orchard environments was also examined. Culturable gram-negative bacteria were surveyed from six experimental apple orchards that had received at least one Kasumin application. In total, 401 Ks(R) isolates (42 different species) were recovered from apple flowers and leaves and orchard soil samples. Although we have not established the presence of a transferrable Ks(R) gene in orchard bacteria, the frequency, number of species, and presence of Ks(R) enterobacterial species in orchard samples suggests the possible role of nontarget bacteria in the future transfer of a Ks(R) gene to E. amylovora. Our data confirm the importance of kasugamycin as an alternate antibiotic for fire blight management and lay the groundwork for the development and incorporation of resistance management strategies.									11	0	10	0	11	0031-949X		WOS:000286644800003	20923369	J	Woodrum, CL; Ewers, FW; Telewski, FW								Hydraulic, biomechanical, and anatomical interactions of xylem from five species of Acer (Aceraceae)								AMERICAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY				90	5			693	699		10.3732/ajb.90.5.693			MAY 2003	2003	Possible trade-offs between hydraulic conductivity and mechanical properties of woody stems from five species were assessed. Acer negundo is a ruderal tree, A. saccharinum, and A. rubrum are fast-growing and shade-intolerant soft maples, whereas A. nigrum and A. saccharum are slow-growing and shade-tolerant hard maples. It was hypothesized that the ruderal and soft maples would have lower modulus of elasticity (MOE) and modulus of rupture (MOR), but higher maximum specific conductivity (K-s max) than hard maples. Many anatomical and general morphological characteristics were measured in an attempt to correlate them to water transport and/or mechanical strength differences between species. No difference was found between species in vessel diameter, fiber wall thickness, initial hydraulic conductivity (K-h initial), specific conductivity (K-s max), native percent embolism, or Huber value. Similarly, no trade-off was found between K-s max and MOE or MOR across the genus. However, fiber lumen diameter was inversely correlated to MOE and MOR. Surprisingly, percentage of ray parenchyma was positively related to MOE. The results suggest transport/mechanical trade-offs do not occur in Acer and differences in mechanical properties may be due to fiber lumen differences that do not influence the efficient transport of water.									26	0	27	0	28	0002-9122		WOS:000183133400004	21659164	J	Domec, JC; Gartner, BL								Relationship between growth rates and xylem hydraulic characteristics in young, mature and old-growth ponderosa pine trees								PLANT CELL AND ENVIRONMENT				26	3			471	483		10.1046/j.1365-3040.2003.00978.x			MAR 2003	2003	The first objective of the present study was to quantify the effects of tree age and stem position on specific conductivity (k(s)), vulnerability to embolism and water storage capacity (capacitance) in trunks of young, mature and old-growth ponderosa pine. The second objective was to determine relationships between hydraulic characteristics and radial and height growth rates to increase the understanding of possible tradeoffs. Within sapwood at all heights and in all ages of trees, outer sapwood had 25-60% higher k (s) than inner sapwood. The water potential at which embolism started (air entry point) was 1.3 MPa lower in inner sapwood than outer sapwood within the mature trees, but there was no difference in the other trees. There was no significant difference in capacitances between the tops of the old growth trees, the mature trees and the young trees. Taking all data together, the capacitances increased sharply with an increase in k(s) and an increase in vulnerability to embolism. The hydraulic characteristics of the three age classes were correlated with the height growth rate but not with the diameter growth rate. Within these age classes, high k(s) was associated with the slowest yearly increase in sapwood area and with a low percentage of latewood, whereas high vulnerability to embolism and high capacitance were more closely associated with high height growth rates.									55	3	52	1	61	0140-7791		WOS:000181648600014		J	Schauer, AJ; Wade, BK; Sowell, JB								Persistence of subalpine forest-meadow ecotones in the Gunnison Basin, Colorado								GREAT BASIN NATURALIST				58	3			273	281					JUL 1998	1998	Forests of the southern Rocky Mountains are punctuated by persistent meadows called parks that are dominated by grasses and forbs. In an attempt to elucidate the maintenance of subalpine parks in the Gunnison Basin, Colorado, soil texture and tree morphology differences along 60-m transects spanning the forest-park ecotone were studied in 6 representative parks. Seedling survivorship, percent seed germination, and soil moisture available to plants were also studied along one of the transects in Willow Park. Soil analyses revealed 40% more silt and significantly less sand and clay in all 6 parks (P < 0.001), which supports the traditional hypothesis that edaphic factors are involved in restricting establishment of trees in par ks. In Willow Park moisture available to plants in soils at field capacity varied significantly across the ecotone (P = 0.011), with 54% more water in forest than in park soils. Measures of growth rate obtained from tree height, dbh, and age were significantly higher nearer the ecotone (P < 0.001). The coefficient of variation of annual-ring width was significantly higher in forest than in ecotone trees (P = 0.002). These results suggest that str.ess of mature Engelmann spruce (Picea engelmannii) and lodgepole pine (Pinus contorta) is an unlikely explanation of park maintenance. P. engelmannii percent seed germination and seedling survivorship were significantly higher in the forest than in the park (P < 0.001). This may be largely due to the more severe seedling microclimate observed in the park. Results indicate that limited seedling establishment is primarily responsible for maintenance of subalpine parks in the Gunnison Basin.									8	0	8	0	8	0017-3614		WOS:000074765200007		