PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Tripathi, S. N.; Raghubanshi, A. S.								Seedling growth of five tropical dry forest tree species in relation to light and nitrogen gradients								JOURNAL OF PLANT ECOLOGY				7	3			250	263		10.1093/jpe/rtt026			JUN 2014	2014	AimsIncreasing anthropogenic nitrogen (N) deposition has been claimed to induce changes in species composition and community dynamics. A greenhouse experiment was conducted to examine the effect of increased N availability on growth and functional attributes of seedlings of five tree species with different life history characteristics under varying irradiances. The following questions have been addressed: (i) how do the pioneer and non-pioneer species respond in absolute growth and relative growth rate (RGR) to the interaction of light and nitrogen? (ii) how does the interaction between irradiance and nitrogen availability modulate growth attributes (i.e. functional attributes)? (iii) is there any variation in growth responses between leguminous and non-leguminous species along the light and nitrogen gradients?MethodsSeedlings of five tree species (Acacia catechu, Bridelia retusa, Dalbergia sissoo, Lagerstroemia parviflora and Terminalia arjuna) were subjected to twelve combinations of irradiance and N levels. Various growth traits, including height (HT), basal area (BA), whole plant dry biomass (M-D), leaf mass per unit area (LMA), leaf area ratio (LAR), net assimilation rate (NAR), RGR, biomass fractions, root-to-shoot ratio (R: S) and leaf nitrogen content, were studied to analyse intra-and inter-specific responses to interacting light and N gradients.Important FindingsSignificant interactions for irradiance and N availability for majority of growth attributes indicates that growth and biomass allocation of seedlings were more responsive to N availability under high irradiance. However, species responded differentially to N addition and they did not follow successional status. Slow growers (B. retusa, a shade-tolerant species and L. parviflora, a light demander) exhibited greater response to N enrichment than the fast growers (A. catechu, D. sissoo and T. arjuna). However, N-mediated increment in growth traits was greater in non-legumes (B. retusa, L. parviflora and T. arjuna) compared with that of legumes (A. catechu and D. sissoo). Allocation of biomass to root was strongly suppressed at the highest N supply across species; however, at high irradiance and high N availability, a greater suppression in R: S ratio was observed for B. retusa. NAR was a stronger determinant of RGR relative to LAR, suggesting its prominent role in increased RGR along increasing irradiances. Overall, a higher growth response of slow-growing species to elevated N levels, particularly the non-pioneers (B. retusa and L. parviflora) suggests that future N deposition may lead to perturbations in competition hierarchies and species composition, ultimately affecting community dynamics in nutrient-poor tropical dry forests.									0	0	0	0	0	1752-9921		WOS:000337063500005		J	Sellin, Arne; Tullus, Arvo; Niglas, Aigar; Ounapuu, Eele; Karusion, Annika; Lohmus, Krista								Humidity-driven changes in growth rate, photosynthetic capacity, hydraulic properties and other functional traits in silver birch (Betula pendula)								ECOLOGICAL RESEARCH				28	3			523	535		10.1007/s11284-013-1041-1			MAY 2013	2013	A study was performed on saplings of silver birch (Betula pendula Roth) growing at the free air humidity manipulation site, which was established to investigate the effect of increased air humidity on tree performance and canopy functioning. The aim of the experiment was to simulate the impact of the increasing atmospheric humidity on forest ecosystems predicted for northern Europe. Artificially elevated relative humidity (RH), which causes transpirational flux to decrease, diminished nutrient supply to the foliage; leaf nitrogen content, phosphorus content and P:N ratio decreased. The changes in leaf nutritional status brought about a considerable decline in both photosynthetic capacity (A (max), V (cmax), J (max)) and tree growth rate. The manipulation induced diverse changes in tree hydraulic architecture and other functional traits. Different segments of the soil-to-leaf water transport pathway responded differently: leaf hydraulic conductance (K (L)) decreased, while hydraulic conductance of root systems (K (R)) and leaf-specific conductivity of stem-wood increased in response to elevated RH. Humidification caused the Huber values of stems to increase, thus reflecting changes in allocation patterns; relatively more resources were allocated to vascular tissue and less to foliage. The elevated RH induced substantial changes in specific leaf area (increased), branch- (decreased) and stem-wood density (decreased). The observed responses suggest that the expected climate-change-induced increase in the growth rate of trees at northern latitudes (boreal areas) due to the earlier start of the growing season in spring or higher carbon assimilation rate could be smaller or null if temperature rise is accompanied by a rise in atmospheric absolute humidity.									7	0	6	0	7	0912-3814		WOS:000318569100016		J	Xu, Chonggang; Fisher, Rosie; Wullschleger, Stan D.; Wilson, Cathy J.; Cai, Michael; McDowell, Nate G.				Fisher, Rosie/E-7746-2013; Wullschleger, Stan/B-8297-2012	Wullschleger, Stan/0000-0002-9869-0446			Toward a Mechanistic Modeling of Nitrogen Limitation on Vegetation Dynamics								PLOS ONE				7	5					e37914	10.1371/journal.pone.0037914			MAY 23 2012	2012	Nitrogen is a dominant regulator of vegetation dynamics, net primary production, and terrestrial carbon cycles; however, most ecosystem models use a rather simplistic relationship between leaf nitrogen content and photosynthetic capacity. Such an approach does not consider how patterns of nitrogen allocation may change with differences in light intensity, growing-season temperature and CO2 concentration. To account for this known variability in nitrogen-photosynthesis relationships, we develop a mechanistic nitrogen allocation model based on a trade-off of nitrogen allocated between growth and storage, and an optimization of nitrogen allocated among light capture, electron transport, carboxylation, and respiration. The developed model is able to predict the acclimation of photosynthetic capacity to changes in CO2 concentration, temperature, and radiation when evaluated against published data of V-c,V-max (maximum carboxylation rate) and J(max) (maximum electron transport rate). A sensitivity analysis of the model for herbaceous plants, deciduous and evergreen trees implies that elevated CO2 concentrations lead to lower allocation of nitrogen to carboxylation but higher allocation to storage. Higher growing-season temperatures cause lower allocation of nitrogen to carboxylation, due to higher nitrogen requirements for light capture pigments and for storage. Lower levels of radiation have a much stronger effect on allocation of nitrogen to carboxylation for herbaceous plants than for trees, resulting from higher nitrogen requirements for light capture for herbaceous plants. As far as we know, this is the first model of complete nitrogen allocation that simultaneously considers nitrogen allocation to light capture, electron transport, carboxylation, respiration and storage, and the responses of each to altered environmental conditions. We expect this model could potentially improve our confidence in simulations of carbon-nitrogen interactions and the vegetation feedbacks to climate in Earth system models.									4	0	4	0	4	1932-6203		WOS:000305335800084	22649564	J	Brym, Zachary T.; Lake, Jeffrey K.; Allen, David; Ostling, Annette								Plant functional traits suggest novel ecological strategy for an invasive shrub in an understorey woody plant community								JOURNAL OF APPLIED ECOLOGY				48	5			1098	1106		10.1111/j.1365-2664.2011.02049.x			OCT 2011	2011	1. Understanding ecological strategies of invasive species relative to the entire native community is important in understanding and managing both the mechanisms and the potential impacts of invasion, but few studies have taken this approach.2. We utilize advances in plant ecology to compare functional traits of an invasive shrub species, autumn-olive Elaeagnus umbellata, to those of the understorey native woody plant community in a southeast Michigan forest. We estimate species trait distributions for six leaf functional traits (specific leaf area, leaf laminar area, leaf dry matter content, leaf nitrogen content, leaf carbon: nitrogen ratio and delta N-15) using a kernel estimator. We then use pairwise trait distance and overlaps to describe the ecological strategy of the invasive shrub relative to that of the native understorey woody plant community.3. The overlap of the invasive shrub's trait distribution with those of the native species was found to be smaller than the overlap of a native shrub's distribution with other native species, consistent with the empty niche hypothesis of invasion. However, the invasive species' mean leaf functional trait values typically fall outside of the range of most native species' mean trait values, suggesting the invasive shrub extends trait space for understorey individuals of the native woody plant community.4. The invasive shrub's leaf trait values are characteristic of a sun-demanding species, contradicting its presence in the shaded forest understorey community and its persistence in an empty niche. We propose that this novel use of leaf functional traits by the invasive shrub could indicate that the invasion is facilitated by additional mechanisms such as release from natural enemies, association with nitrogen-fixing bacteria, use of an empty temporal niche (namely the light available to the understorey early in the growing season), bird dispersal or some synthesis of these factors.5. Synthesis and applications. This study develops plant functional trait theory by studying an invasive species within the context of the entire native woody plant community. The approach can improve our understanding of the potential mechanisms of an invasion event and suggest ecological consequences and related management strategies for the maintenance of native forest communities. Specifically, this study, along with known data on the invasive species, suggests aggressive management in sunny gap and edge habitat provides the best strategy for long-term control.									6	0	5	0	6	0021-8901		WOS:000295095100005		J	Sugiura, Daisuke; Tateno, Masaki								Optimal Leaf-to-Root Ratio and Leaf Nitrogen Content Determined by Light and Nitrogen Availabilities								PLOS ONE				6	7					e22236	10.1371/journal.pone.0022236			JUL 12 2011	2011	Plants exhibit higher leaf-to-root ratios (L/R) and lower leaf nitrogen content (N(area)) in low-light than in high-light environments, but an ecological significance of this trait has not been explained from a whole-plant perspective. This study aimed to theoretically and experimentally demonstrate whether these observed L/R and N(area) are explained as optimal biomass allocation that maximize whole-plant relative growth rate (RGR). We developed a model which predicts optimal L/R and N(area) in response to nitrogen and light availability. In the model, net assimilation rate (NAR) was determined by light-photosynthesis curve, light availability measured during experiments, and leaf temperature affecting the photosynthesis and leaf dark respiration rate in high and low-light environments. Two pioneer trees, Morus bombycis and Acer buergerianum, were grown in various light and nitrogen availabilities in an experimental garden and used for parameterizing and testing the model predictions. They were grouped into four treatment groups (relative photosynthetic photon flux density, RPPFD 100% or 10% x nitrogen-rich or nitrogen-poor conditions) and grown in an experimental garden for 60 to 100 days. The model predicted that optimal L/R is higher and N(area) is lower in low-light than high-light environments when compared in the same soil nitrogen availability. Observed L/R and N(area) of the two pioneer trees were close to the predicted optimums. From the model predictions and pot experiments, we conclude that the pioneer trees, M. bombycis and A. buergerianum, regulated L/R and N(area) to maximize RGR in response to nitrogen and light availability.									9	1	7	0	9	1932-6203		WOS:000292699000033	21765957	J	Tanaka-Oda, Ayumi; Kenzo, Tanaka; Koretsune, Satomi; Sasaki, Haruto; Fukuda, Kenji				Ayumi, Tanaka-Oda/D-4780-2012				Ontogenetic changes in water-use efficiency (delta C-13) and leaf traits differ among tree species growing in a semiarid region of the Loess Plateau, China								FOREST ECOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT				259	5			953	957		10.1016/j.foreco.2009.11.037			FEB 20 2010	2010	On the Loess Plateau, China, several planted tree species such as Populus hopeinsis and Robinia pseudoacacia suffer occasional diebacks in the top shoots, reducing growth rates after maturation. However, this does not usually occur in other species, e.g., Ulmus pumila and Zizyphus jujuba. We compared stable carbon isotope ratios (delta C-13) as indicators of leaf water-use efficiency (WUE), leaf mass per unit area (LMA), and leaf area- and mass-based nitrogen content (N-area and N-mass) by tree height (1, 5, and 10 m) in P. hopeinsis, R. pseudoacacia, U. pumila, and Z jujuba. In P. hopeinsis and R. pseudoacacia, leaf delta C-13 and N-area were significantly lower in 10-m trees than in 1-m saplings, indicating that leaf WUE and photosynthetic rates of both species decreased with tree height. In contrast, delta C-13 in Z. jujuba varied little with tree height. The delta C-13 of 10-m-tall U. pumila trees was significantly higher than that of 1-m plants, demonstrating an increase in WUE with tree height. Decreasing WUE, leaf N-area and N-mass with height increases in P. hopeinsis and R. pseudoacacia may be related to water and nutrient limitations for these species in semiarid regions. in contrast, stable or increasing delta C-13 with tree height in U. pumila and Z jujuba may account (to some extent) for successful production of these species under identical environmental conditions. Diameter growth rate also decreased with maturity in P. hopeinsis and R. pseudoacacia, but increased or was stable for U. pumila and Z. jujuba. The differences in leaf WUE and LMA among species with tree maturity may be related to species' growth patterns and susceptibility to drought stress, and are likely to be important new criteria for plantation species selection on the Loess Plateau. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.									3	7	5	0	11	0378-1127		WOS:000275223300011		J	Cornwell, William K.; Ackerly, David D.				Ackerly, David/A-1247-2009	Ackerly, David/0000-0002-1847-7398			Community assembly and shifts in plant trait distributions across an environmental gradient in coastal California								ECOLOGICAL MONOGRAPHS				79	1			109	126		10.1890/07-1134.1			FEB 2009	2009	Community assembly processes are thought to shape the mean, spread, and spacing of functional trait values within communities. Two broad categories of assembly processes have been proposed: first, a habitat filter that restricts the range of viable strategies and second, a partitioning of microsites and/or resources that leads to a limit to the similarity of coexisting species. The strength of both processes may be dependent on conditions at a particular site and may change along an abiotic gradient.We sampled environmental variables and plant communities in 44 plots across the varied topography of a coastal California landscape. We characterized 14 leaf, stem, and root traits for 54 woody plant species, including detailed intraspecific data for two traits with the goal of understanding the connection between traits and assembly processes in a variety of environmental conditions.We examined the within-community mean, range, variance, kurtosis, and other measures of spacing of trait values. In this landscape, there was a topographically mediated gradient in water availability. Across this gradient we observed strong shifts in both the plot-level mean trait values and the variation in trait values within communities. Trends in trait means with the environment were due largely to species turnover, with intraspecific shifts playing a smaller role. Traits associated with a vertical partitioning of light showed a greater range and variance on the wet soils, while nitrogen per area, which is associated with water use efficiency, showed a greater spread on the dry soils.We found strong nonrandom patterns in the trait distributions consistent with expectations based on trait-mediated community assembly. There was a significant reduction in the range of six out of 11 leaf and stem functional trait values relative to a null model. For specific leaf area (SLA) we found a significant even spacing of trait values relative to the null model. For seed size we found a more platykurtic distribution than expected. These results suggest that both a habitat filter and a limit to the similarity of coexisting species can simultaneously shape the distribution of traits and the assembly of local plant communities.									203	13	200	0	219	0012-9615		WOS:000263566600006		J	Suwa, Rempei; Analuddin, Kangkuso; Khan, Md. Nabiul Islam; Hagihara, Akio								Structure and productivity along a tree height gradient in a Kandelia obovata mangrove forest in the Manko Wetland, Okinawa Island, Japan								Wetlands Ecology and Management				16	4			331	343		10.1007/s11273-007-9071-5			AUG 2008	2008	Tree height (H) of Kandelia obovata trees decreased sharply from 5 m at the forest interior behind the terrestrial forest to 1.5 m at the forest edge near the river bank according to an increase in the yearly waterlogged period along a belt transect. The decreasing tree stature was attributed to a decrease in the asymptote of H in the D-0.1 (stem diameter at H/10)-H relationship toward the edge. The K. obovata trees were well classified into interior and edge types using a discriminant function based on the habitat-specific D-0.1-H relationships. Allometric equations, as a function of (D0.1H)-H-2, differed significantly between the interior and edge types in the estimation of the phytomasses of stems and leaves, and the leaf area per tree. On the other hand, common allometric equations were successfully established in the estimation of respective phytomasses of aboveground parts and branches. Biomass and leaf area index decreased toward the forest edge. The biomass allocation to stems decreased toward the edge, whereas those to branches and leaves increased. A dramatic change in stem diameter increment resulted in differences in the D-0.1-H relationship along the tree height gradient. Relative growth rate of biomass and light-saturated net photosynthesis, which paralleled net assimilation rate from the interior to the edge, showed their maximum peaks in the middle of the belt transect. This indicates that there exists an optimal environmental condition for growth of K. obovata trees. Leaf nitrogen content tended to increase to the edge with increasing waterlogged period.									5	1	4	0	6	0923-4861		BCI:BCI200800539085		J	Ronnberg-Wastljung, AC; Glynn, C; Weih, M				Weih, Martin/H-5093-2011				QTL analyses of drought tolerance and growth for a Salix dasyclados x Salix viminalis hybrid in contrasting water regimes								THEORETICAL AND APPLIED GENETICS				110	3			537	549		10.1007/s00122-004-1866-7			FEB 2005	2005	Quantitative trait loci (QTL) for growth traits and water-use efficiency have been identified in two water regimes (normal and drought-treated) and for a treatment index. A tetraploid hybrid F-2 population originating from a cross between a Salix dasyclados clone (SW901290) and a Salix viminalis clone ('Jorunn') was used in the study. The growth response of each individual including both above and below ground dry-matter production (i.e. shoot length, shoot diameter, aboveground and root dry weight, internode length, root dry weight/total dry weight, relative growth rate and leaf nitrogen content) was analysed in a replicated block experiment with two water treatments. A composite interval mapping approach was used to estimate number of QTL, the magnitude of the QTL and their position on genetic linkage maps. QTL specific for each treatment and for the treatment index were found, but QTL common across the treatments and the treatment index were also detected. Each QTL explained from 8% to 29% of the phenotypic variation, depending on trait and treatment. Clusters of QTL for different traits were mapped close to each other at several linkage groups, indicating either a common genetic base or tightly linked QTL. Common QTL identified between treatments and treatment index in the complex trait dry weight can be useful tools in the breeding and selection for drought stress tolerance in Salix.Quantitative trait loci (QTL) for growth traits and water-use efficiency have been identified in two water regimes (normal and drought-treated) and for a treatment index. A tetraploid hybrid F-2 population originating from a cross between a Salix dasyclados clone (SW901290) and a Salix viminalis clone ('Jorunn') was used in the study. The growth response of each individual including both above and below ground dry-matter production (i.e. shoot length, shoot diameter, aboveground and root dry weight, internode length, root dry weight/total dry weight, relative growth rate and leaf nitrogen content) was analysed in a replicated block experiment with two water treatments. A composite interval mapping approach was used to estimate number of QTL, the magnitude of the QTL and their position on genetic linkage maps. QTL specific for each treatment and for the treatment index were found, but QTL common across the treatments and the treatment index were also detected. Each QTL explained from 8% to 29% of the phenotypic variation, depending on trait and treatment. Clusters of QTL for different traits were mapped close to each other at several linkage groups, indicating either a common genetic base or tightly linked QTL. Common QTL identified between treatments and treatment index in the complex trait dry weight can be useful tools in the breeding and selection for drought stress tolerance in Salix.									33	4	26	0	38	0040-5752		WOS:000227049900014	15619077	J	Montgomery, R				Montgomery, Rebecca/J-5774-2013	Montgomery, Rebecca/0000-0002-4131-1847			Relative importance of photosynthetic physiology and biomass allocation for tree seedling growth across a broad light gradient								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				24	2			155	167					FEB 2004	2004	Studies of tree seedling physiology and growth under field conditions provide information on the mechanisms underlying inter- and intraspecific differences in growth and survival at a critical period during forest regeneration. I compared photosynthetic physiology, growth and biomass allocation in seedlings of three shade-tolerant tree species, Virola koschynii Warb., Dipteryx panamensis (Pittier) Record & Mell and Brosimum alicastrum Swartz., growing across a light gradient created by a forest-pasture edge (0.5 to 67% diffuse transmittance (%T)). Most growth and physiological traits showed nonlinear responses to light availability, with the greatest changes occurring between 0.5 and 20 %T. Specific leaf area (SLA) and nitrogen per unit leaf mass (N(mass)) decreased, maximum assimilation per unit leaf area (A(area)) and area-based leaf N concentration (N(area)) increased, and maximum assimilation per unit leaf mass (A(mass)) did not change with increasing irradiance. Plastic responses in SLA were important determinants of leaf N and A a across the gradient. Species differed in magnitude and plasticity of growth; B. alicastrum had the lowest relative growth rates (RGR) and low plasticity. Its final biomass varied only 10-fold across the light gradient. In contrast, the final biomass of D. panamensis and V koschynii varied by 100- and 50-fold, respectively, and both had higher RGR than B. alicastrum. As light availability increased, all species decreased biomass allocation to leaf tissue (mass and area) and showed a trade-off between allocation to leaf area at a given plant mass (LAR) and net gain in mass per unit leaf area (net assimilation rate, NAR). This trade-off largely reflected declines in SLA with increasing light. Finally, A(area) was correlated with NAR and both were major determinants of intraspecific variation in RGR. These data indicate the importance of plasticity in photosynthetic physiology and allocation for variation in tree seedling growth among habitats that vary in light availability.									34	0	34	1	35	0829-318X		WOS:000188786300003	14676032	J	Mediavilla, S; Escudero, A								Relative growth rate of leaf biomass and leaf nitrogen content in several mediterranean woody species								PLANT ECOLOGY				168	2			321	332		10.1023/A:1024496717918			SEP 2003	2003	In many plant species, herbivory is a major determinant of leaf mortality and it can cause a strong reduction in productive potential. Most predation occurs on young, expanding leaves. Thus, a rapid growth of the leaves can reduce the impact of predation. Furthermore, in cold Mediterranean climates the length of the growing season is constrained to a short period in spring and early summer owing both to low winter temperatures and drought stress in early summer. Therefore, a rapid deployment of leaf area and a high photosynthetic capacity during the spring and early summer might have important positive effects on the final carbon balance of the leaf population. Relative growth rates (RGR) of leaf biomass were measured in 19 woody species typical of Central Western Spain with deciduous and evergreen habits. Highly significant differences were detected in the leaf growth rate of the different species. The differences between species, however, did not correlate either with the mean leaf life-span of each of the species or with other leaf traits such as photosynthetic capacity, specific leaf area or nitrogen content. Leaf growth rate was positively correlated with time elapsed between leaf initiation and fruit maturation, so that species with fruit dispersal in spring and early summer in general had lower leaf growth rates than species with autumn fruit shedding. This relationship shows the effects of the concurrence between vegetative and reproductive organs for nutrients and other resources. Nitrogen concentration in the leaves was very high at the time of bud break, and declined during leaf expansion owing to the dilution associated with the increase in structural components. The rate of nitrogen dilution was, thus, positively related to the leaf growth rate. Relative growth rates calculated for nitrogen mass in leaves were very low compared to the growth in total mass. This suggests that most leaf nitrogen is translocated from the plant stores to the leaf biomass before the start of leaf expansion and that the contribution of root uptake during leaf expansion is comparatively low.									24	0	22	0	27	1385-0237		WOS:000183836200011		J	Weih, M; Karlsson, PS				Weih, Martin/H-5093-2011; Karlsson, Staffan/J-3082-2012	Karlsson, Staffan/0000-0002-5739-5213			Growth response of Mountain birch to air and soil temperature: is increasing leaf-nitrogen content an acclimation to lower air temperature?								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				150	1			147	155		10.1046/j.1469-8137.2001.00078.x			APR 2001	2001	Growth and nitrogen (N) economy of mountain birch are reported here in response to temperature change. Mechanisms of temperature effects on plant growth in temperate - arctic regions are discussed in the light of decreasing growth rates and increasing leaf-N contents along altitudinal and latitudinal temperature gradients.Mountain birch (Betula pubescens ssp. czerepanovii) seedlings were grown at two soil temperatures, air temperatures and nutrient concentrations in a full-factorial experiment during one growing season in northern Sweden.Changes in air and soil temperature affected aboveground growth more than belowground growth. An increase in air temperature increased leaf area ratio and plant-N productivity while decreasing plant-N concentration and leaf-N content. A change in soil temperature affected root-N uptake rate and plant-N concentration, similar to the effect of a change in nutrient supply. Air and soil temperature had interactive effects on growth rate, N productivity and leaf-N content.The results indicate that increasing leaf-N content with increasing altitude and latitude is not only a passive consequence of weaker N dilution by reduced growth, but also a physiological acclimation to lower air temperature.									67	3	62	0	70	0028-646X		WOS:000167774100015		J	Wright, IJ; Westoby, M				Wright, Ian/G-4979-2012	Wright, Ian/0000-0001-8338-9143			Understanding seedling growth relationships through specific leaf area and leaf nitrogen concentration: generalisations across growth forms and growth irradiance								OECOLOGIA				127	1			21	29		10.1007/s004420000554			MAR 2001	2001	Seedling relative growth rate (RGR) achieved under favourable growth conditions can be thought of as a useful bioassay of the potential ability of species to take advantage of favourable growth opportunities; that is, of a species' growth strategy. The consistency of relationships between RGR and its component attributes leaf nitrogen productivity (LNP), leaf N per area (LNCa), specific leaf area (SLA) and leaf mass ratio (LMR) was assessed across 12 datasets comprising three growth forms (grasses, herbaceous dicots and woody plants; 250 species in total). These relationships were characterised in terms of scaling slopes (regressions on log-log axes, the slopes giving the proportional relationship between the variables). Mathematically, the expected scaling slope between RGR and each component is 1.0, giving an appropriate null hypothesis to test against (whereas the widely used null hypothesis of zero correlation is in fact inappropriate for this situation). Deviations below 1:1 scaling slopes indicate negative covariance between the components. Consequently, the correlation structure between the components of RGR should also be investigated. Biologically, RGR should scale 1:1 with SLA at a given LNCa and somewhat more weakly with LNCa at a given SLA. SLA and LNCa should themselves scale with a slope of between 0 and -1, with the actual slope indicating the extent to which between-species variation in SLA dilutes leaf N on an area basis versus the ability of species to maintain LNCa at a given growth irradiance. On average, across the 12 datasets RGR scaled close-to-proportionally with SLA, and 1:1 with SLA at a given LNCa. RGR scaled with LNCa with null or negative slopes, since SLA and LNCa scaled negatively (with slopes generally shallower than -1); however, RGR scaled positively (but less than proportionally) with LNCa at a given SLA. For these key relationships there were no qualitatively different conclusions with respect to the growth form under consideration or the growth irradiance at which the seedlings were grown. RGR also scaled close-to-proportionally with LNP, while LNP and LNCa were negatively associated. These relationships involving LNP are difficult to interpret since it can be shown that they are, at least potentially, the result of the interactions between RGR, SLA and LNCa, as well as reflecting intrinsic differences in the efficiency of nitrogen use in the growth process.									51	3	49	3	56	0029-8549		WOS:000167629200003		J	Rijkers, T; Pons, TL; Bongers, F								The effect of tree height and light availability on photosynthetic leaf traits of four neotropical species differing in shade tolerance								FUNCTIONAL ECOLOGY				14	1			77	86		10.1046/j.1365-2435.2000.00395.x			FEB 2000	2000	1. Light-saturated rate of photosynthesis (A(max)), nitrogen (N), chlorophyll (Chl) content and leaf mass per unit area (LMA) were measured in leaves of trees of different heights along a natural light gradient in a French Guiana rain forest. The following four species, arranged in order from most shade-tolerant to pioneer, were studied: Duguetia surinamensis, Vouacapoua americana, Dicorynia guianensis and Goupia glabra. Light availability of trees was estimated using hemispherical photography.2. The pioneer species Goupia had the lowest LMA and leaf N on both an area and mass basis, whereas Duguetia had the highest values. In general, leaf variables of Vouacapoua and Dicorynia tended to be intermediates. Because A(max)/area was similar among species, Goupia showed both a much higher light-saturated photosynthetic nitrogen-use efficiency (PNUEmax) and A(max)/mass. Leaves of Vouacapoua demonstrated the greatest plasticity in A(max)/area, particularly in small saplings.3. A distinction could be made between the effect of tree height and light availability on the structural, i.e. LMA, and photosynthetic leaf characteristics of all four species. The direction and magnitude of the variation in variables were similar among species.4. LMA was the key variable that mainly determined variation in the other leaf variables along tree height and light availability gradients, with the exception of changes in chlorophyll concentration. A(max)/area, N/area, LMA and stomatal conductance to water vapour (g(s)) increased, whereas Chl/mass decreased, with both increasing tree height and canopy openness. A(max)/mass, PNUEmax and A(max)/Chl increased with increasing openness only. N/mass and Chl/area were independent of tree height and openness, except for small saplings of Goupia which had a much lower Chl/area.									97	10	96	3	107	0269-8463		WOS:000086232500011		J	Williams, RS; Lincoln, DE; Norby, RJ				Norby, Richard/C-1773-2012				Leaf age effects of elevated CO(2)-grown white oak leaves on spring-feeding lepidopterans								GLOBAL CHANGE BIOLOGY				4	3			235	246		10.1046/j.1365-2486.1998.00127.x			MAR 1998	1998	Folivorous insect responses to elevated CO(2)-grown tree species may be complicated by phytochemical changes as leaves age. For example, young expanding leaves in tree species may be less affected by enriched CO(2)-alterations in leaf phytochemistry than older mature leaves due to shorter exposure times to elevated CO(2) atmospheres. This, in turn, could result in different effects on early vs. late instar larvae of herbivorous insects. To address this, seedlings of white oak (Quercus alba L.), grown in open-top chambers under ambient and elevated CO(2), were fed to two important early spring feeding herbivores; gypsy moth (Lymantria dispar L.), and forest tent caterpillar (Malacosoma disstria Hubner). Young, expanding leaves were presented to early instar larvae, and older fully expanded or mature leaves to late instar larvae. Young leaves had significantly lower leaf nitrogen content and significantly higher total nonstructural carbohydrate:nitrogen ratio as plant CO(2) concentration rose, while nonstructural carbohydrates and total carbon-based phenolics were unaffected by plant CO(2) treatment. These phytochemical changes contributed to a significant reduction in the growth rate of early instar gypsy moth larvae, while growth rates of forest tent caterpillar were unaffected. The differences in insect responses were attributed to an increase in the nitrogen utilization efficiency (NUE) of early instar forest tent caterpillar larvae feeding on elevated CO(2)-grown leaves, while early instar gypsy moth larval NUE remained unchanged among the treatments. Later instar larvae of both insect species experienced larger reductions in foliage quality on elevated CO(2)-grown leaves than earlier instars, as the carbohydrate:nitrogen ratio of leaves substantially increased. Despite this, neither insect species exhibited changes in growth or consumption rates between CO(2) treatments in the later instar. An increase in NUE was apparently responsible for offsetting reduced foliar nitrogen for the late instar larvae of both species.									46	15	39	0	62	1354-1013		WOS:000072857700001		J	Cornelissen, JHC; Werger, MJA; CastroDiez, P; vanRheenen, JWA; Rowland, AP				Rowland, Alan/A-9793-2013; Castro, Pilar/L-4716-2014	Rowland, Alan/0000-0001-7499-8473; 			Foliar nutrients in relation to growth, allocation and leaf traits in seedlings of a wide range of woody plant species and types								OECOLOGIA				111	4			460	469		10.1007/s004420050259			AUG 1997	1997	This study aimed to identify functional correlates of seedling leaf nutrient content among woody species and to characterise functional species groups with respect to leaf nutrient attributes. Seedlings of 81 woody species from the temperate zone of western Europe were grown in a standard laboratory environment with standard, near-optimal nutrient availability. Weight-based leaf N content (N-wght) was positively correlated with mean relative growth rate (RGR), but the correlation with mean RGR was tighter when leaf N was expressed on a whole-plant weight basis: leaf nitrogen weight ratio (LNWR). Area-based leaf N content (N-area) was not associated with mean RGR, but was closely correlated with the quotient of saturated leaf weight and leaf area. Weight-based leaf K content (K-wght) was a close correlate of the saturated/dry weight ratio of the foliage, Within the lower range, K-wght corresponded with growth-related nutrient attributes, but higher values appeared to indicate succulence or remobilisable stored water. Functional groups of species and genera could be distinguished with respect to seedling leaf nutrient attributes. Deciduous woody climbers and scramblers had consistently higher leaf N-wght, LNWR and (apparently) leaf K-wght than other deciduous species or genera, and shrubs had higher values than trees. These differences seemed due partly to variation in specific leaf area. Evergreens had consistently higher leaf N-area than deciduous plants, but there were no significant differences in weight-based leaf nutrient attributes between these two groups, possibly because of 'luxury nutrient consumption' by the slow-growing evergreens. Another functional group was that of the nitrogen-fixing species, which had consistently high innate leaf N-wght compared to non-N-fixers. The ecological significance of the leaf nutrient attributes in this study is discussed by comparing the seedling data with those from field-collected material, and by brief reference to the natural habitats of the species.									98	2	90	0	101	0029-8549		WOS:A1997XR38100003		J	Dias, MB								Physiological response of Solanum crinitum Lam to contrasting light environments								PESQUISA AGROPECUARIA BRASILEIRA				32	8			789	796					AUG 1997	1997	During a 66-day period, a study was made in controlled environment chambers, under high (800-1000 mu mol m(-2) s(-1)) and low (200-350 mu mol m(-2) s(-1)) light regimes on the physiology, morphology and growth of Solanum crinitum, a pioneer medium-sized woody species known to invade forest gaps, active pastures and abandoned agricultural areas in the Brazilian Amazonia. The objective was to investigate the sun-shade acclimation characteristics of this species. High-light grown plants (HL) had higher light saturated rates of photosynthesis than low-light plants (LL). No significant difference in dark respiration was observed between light regimes. Relative growth rate was initially (at 22 d) higher for HL, becoming similar between treatments in the last two harvests (44 and 66 d). Leaf area ratio and specific leaf area were higher for LL. Allocation of biomass to leaves was similar between treatments, while biomass allocated to roots was higher in HL. Allocation of biomass to stems was higher in LL. Leaves grown under high irradiance had less nitrogen per unit of mass and more per unit of area than leaves developed at low irradiance. These results suggest that light is important to the performance of this species and that the differential responses to light conditions may contribute to or detract from its ability to succeed in natural and agricultural environments or to endure control strategies.									8	0	6	13	18	0100-204X		WOS:A1997XT66900004		J	WILLIAMS, RS; LINCOLN, DE; THOMAS, RB								LOBLOLLY-PINE GROWN UNDER ELEVATED CO2 AFFECTS EARLY INSTAR PINE SAWFLY PERFORMANCE								OECOLOGIA				98	1			64	71		10.1007/BF00326091			JUN 1994	1994	Seedlings of loblolly pine Pinus taeda (L.), were grown in open-topped field chambers under three CO2 regimes: ambient, 150 mul l-1 CO2 above ambient, and 300 mul l-1 CO2 above ambient. A fourth, non-chambered ambient treatment was included to assess chamber effects. Needles were used in 96 h feeding trials to determine the performance of young, second instar larvae of loblolly pine's principal leaf herbivore, red-headed pine sawfly, Neodiprion lecontei (Fitch). The relative consumption rate of larvae significantly increased on plants grown under elevated CO2, and needles grown in the highest CO2 regime were consumed 21% more rapidly than needles grown in ambient CO2. Both the significant decline in leaf nitrogen content and the substantial increase in leaf starch content contributed to a significant increase in the starch:nitrogen ratio in plants grown in elevated CO2. Insect consumption rate was negatively related to leaf nitrogen content and positively related to the starch:nitrogen ratio. Of the four volatile leaf monoterpenes measured, only beta-pinene exhibited a significant CO2 effect and declined in plants grown in elevated CO2. Although consumption changed, the relative growth rates of larvae were not different among CO2 treatments. Despite lower nitrogen consumption rates by larvae feeding on the plants grown in elevated CO2, nitrogen accumulation rates were the same for all treatments due to a significant increase in nitrogen utilization efficiency. The ability of this insect to respond at an early, potentially susceptible larval stage to poorer food quality and declining levels of a leaf monoterpene suggest that changes in needle quality within pines in future elevated-CO2 atmospheres may not especially affect young insects and that tree-feeding sawflies may respond in a manner similar to herb-feeding lepidopterans.									71	4	47	0	76	0029-8549		WOS:A1994NR69600009		J	JACOBSEN, D; SANDJENSEN, K				Jacobsen, Dean/K-4920-2014	Jacobsen, Dean/0000-0001-5137-297X			GROWTH AND ENERGETICS OF A TRICHOPTERAN LARVA FEEDING ON FRESH SUBMERGED AND TERRESTRIAL PLANTS								OECOLOGIA				97	3			412	418					APR 1994	1994	We studied the growth and assimilation of larvae of Anabolia nervosa, a lotic trichopteran shredder, on diets of fresh tissue of the submerged macrophyte Potamogeton perfoliatus and fresh leaves of the trees Alnus glutinosa and Fagus sylvatica. Fifth-in-star larvae were fed these three diets for 23 days (20 May-12 June) in the laboratory. Instantaneous growth rate and gross growth efficiency were almost the same for larvae fed Potamogeton and Alnus, but lower for larvae fed Fagus. The larvae consumed 3 times more fresh Potamogeton than Alnus leaves, but the same amounts in terms of dry mass. The consumption of fresh Fagus was initially twice that of the two other food items but dropped rapidly during the experiment, following the marked seasonal decline of leaf nitrogen content. Allocation patterns of fat and protein differed among food sources. Larvae grown on Alnus accumulated more fat than larvae grown on Potamogeton, while the reverse was true for protein accumulation. The assimilation efficiency based on carbon units was the same (44%) for all three food items and was among the highest reported for shredding caddis larvae. The study demonstrates that fresh tissue of Potamogeton perfoliatus provides a valuable food source to the facultative shredder herbivore Anabolia nervosa.									20	0	16	0	20	0029-8549		WOS:A1994NH87700017		J	REICH, PB; WALTERS, MB; ELLSWORTH, DS								LEAF LIFE-SPAN IN RELATION TO LEAF, PLANT, AND STAND CHARACTERISTICS AMONG DIVERSE ECOSYSTEMS								ECOLOGICAL MONOGRAPHS				62	3			365	392		10.2307/2937116			SEP 1992	1992	Variation in leaf life-span has long been considered of ecological significance. Despite this, quantitative evaluation of the relationships between leaf life-span and other plant and ecosystem characteristics has been rare. In this paper we ask whether leaf life-span is related to other leaf, plant, and stand traits of species from diverse ecosystems and biomes. We also examine the interaction between leaf, plant, and stand traits and their relation to productivity and ecological patterns.Among all species, both mass- (A(mass)) and area-based (A(area)) maximum net photosynthesis decreased with increasing leaf life-span, but the relationship was stronger on a mass (P < .001, r2 = 0.70) than an area (P < .05, r2 = 0.24) basis. Similarly, mass-based leaf nitrogen (leaf N(mass)) decreased (P < .001, r2 = 0.52) with leaf life-span, but area-based leaf N (leaf N(area)) did not (P > .25, r2 = 0.01). Specific leaf area (SLA, leaf area/leaf dry mass) and leaf diffusive conductance also decreased with increasing leaf life-span. Decreasing A(mass) with increasing leaf life-span results from the impact of decreasing N(mass) and SLA on A(mass). Variation in leaf traits as a function of leaf life-span was similar for broad-leaved and needle-leaved subsets of the data. These leaf-scale data from several biomes were compared to a data set from a single biome, Amazonia. For several leaf traits (e.g., SLA, N(mass), and A(mass)) the quantitative relationship with leaf life-span was similar in the two independent data sets, suggesting that these are fundamental relations applicable to all species. A(mass) was a linear function of N(mass)(P < .001, r2 = 0.74) with a regression similar to previous analyses, while A(area) was not significantly related to N(area). These results suggest that the photosynthesis-leaf N relationship among species should be considered universal when expressed on a mass, but not on a leaf area, basis.Relative growth rates (RGR) and leaf area ratio (LAR, the whole-plant ratio of leaf area to total dry mass) of seedlings decreased with increasing leaf life-span (P < .001, r2 = 0.61 and 0.89, respectively). LAR was positively related to both RGR and A(mass)(r2 = 0.68 and 0.84, respectively), and A(mass) and RGR were also positively related (r2 = 0.55). Absolute height growth rates of young trees decreased with increasing leaf life-span (P < .001, r2 = 0.72) and increased with A(mass)(P < .001, r2 = 0.78). It appears that a suite of traits including short leaf life-span and high leaf N(mass), SLA, LAR, and A(mass) interactively contribute to high growth rates in open-grown individuals.These traits interact similarly at the stand level, but stands differ from individuals in one key trait. In closed-canopy forests, species with longer lived foliage (and low LAR as seedlings) have greater foliage mass per unit ground area (P < .001, r2 = 0.74) and a greater proportion of total mass in foliage. The aboveground production efficiency (ANPP/foliar biomass) of forest stands decreased markedly with increasing leaf life-span or total foliage mass (P < .001, r2 = 0.78 and 0.72, respectively), probably as a result of decreasing A(mass), N(mass), and SLA, all of which were positively related with production efficiency and negatively related to total foliage mass. However, high foliage mass of species with extended leaflife-spans appears to compensate for low production per unit foliage, since aboveground net primary production (ANPP, in megagrams per hectare per year) of forest stands was not related to leaf life-span. Extended leaf life-span also appears to compensate for lower potential production per unit leaf N per unit time, with the result that stand-level N use efficiency is weakly positively related to leaf life-span.We hypothesize that co-variation among species in leaf life-span, SLA, leaf N(mass), A(mass), and growth rate reflects a set of mutually supporting traits that interact to determine plant behavior and production, and provide a useful conceptual link between processes at short-term leaf scales and longer term whole plant and stand-level scales. Although this paper has focused on leaf-span, this trait is so closely interrelated with several others that this cohort of leaf traits should be viewed as causally interrelated. Generality in the relationships between leaf life-span and other plant traits across diverse communities and ecosystems suggests that they are universal in nature and thus can provide a quantitative link and/or common currency for ecological comparisons among diverse systems.									807	62	763	7	900	0012-9615		WOS:A1992JJ41600003		J	BACH, CE								PLANT SUCCESSIONAL STAGE AND INSECT HERBIVORY - FLEA BEETLES ON SAND-DUNE WILLOW								ECOLOGY				71	2			598	609		10.2307/1940313			APR 1990	1990										20	0	18	0	20	0012-9658		WOS:A1990CV62800019		