PT	AU	BA	CA	GP	RI	OI	BE	Z2	TI	X1	Y1	Z1	FT	PN	AE	Z3	SO	S1	SE	BS	VL	IS	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	SU	PD	PY	AB	X4	Y4	Z4	AK	CT	CY	SP	CL	TC	Z8	ZB	ZS	Z9	SN	BN	UT	PM	J	Chaturvedi, R. K.; Raghubanshi, A. S.; Singh, J. S.								Growth of tree seedlings in a tropical dry forest in relation to soil moisture and leaf traits								JOURNAL OF PLANT ECOLOGY				6	2			158	170		10.1093/jpe/rts025			APR 2013	2013	The growth of plant species in tropical dry forest (TDF) is expected to be largely governed by the availability of soil moisture. In this study we attempt to identify mechanisms by which seedlings of dry tropical trees cope with water stress by adjusting their leaf characteristics to water availability and micro environments, and address following questions: How are leaf traits and relative growth rate (RGR) of the dominant seedling species of TDF affected by seasonal changes in soil moisture content (SMC)? What is the relationship of functional traits with each other? Can leaf traits singly or in combination predict the growth rate of seedling species of TDF? The study was conducted in situ on four sites (viz., Hathinala, Gaighat, Harnakachar and Ranitali, listed in order of decreasing SMC) within the tropical dry deciduous forest in northern India.Five leaf traits viz., specific leaf area (SLA), leaf dry matter content (LDMC), concentrations of leaf nitrogen (leaf N), phosphorus (leaf P) and chlorophyll (Chl) and two physiological processes, viz., stomatal conductance (Gs(net)) and photosynthetic rate (A(net)), and RGR, of four dominant tree seedling species of a TDF (viz., Buchanania lanzan, Diospyros melanoxylon, Shorea robusta and Terminalia tomentosa) on four sites were analysed for species, site and season effects over a 2-year period. Step-wise multiple regression was performed to predict RGR from mean values of SMC, leaf traits and physiological processes. Principal component analysis (PCA) was performed to observe the extent of intra- vs. inter-specific variability in the leaf traits and physiological rates.All the traits and physiological rates were interrelated and showed significant positive relationship with RGR except for the correlation of LDMC with RGR which was not significant. Further, relationships of SMC with all leaf traits, physiological rates and RGR were significant, except for that between SMC and SLA for B. lanzan and D. melanoxylon. The slope of seedling trait:SMC relationship, a measure of phenotypic plasticity in response to soil moisture gradient, varied among species. Among the four species, T. tomentosa was the most plastic and S. robusta the least.In conclusion, leaf traits and physiological processes were strongly related to soil water availability on the one hand and seedling growth on the other. Gs(net) is the most important variable which accounted for the greatest amount of variability (62%) in RGR, emphasizing the role of stomatal conductance in shaping growth patterns across spatial and temporal gradients of soil water availability. Gs(net) and SMC together explained 64% variability in RGR, indicating that other traits/factors, not studied by us are also important in modulating the growth of tropical tree seedlings.									1	0	1	0	1	1752-9921		WOS:000316964200006		J	Chu, Ziyan; Lu, Yijun; Chang, Jie; Wang, Meng; Jiang, Hong; He, Jinsheng; Peng, Changhui; Ge, Ying				He, Jin-Sheng/A-4053-2009; Peng, Changhui/G-8248-2012				Leaf respiration/photosynthesis relationship and variation: an investigation of 39 woody and herbaceous species in east subtropical China								TREES-STRUCTURE AND FUNCTION				25	2			301	310		10.1007/s00468-010-0506-x			APR 2011	2011	Thirty-nine plant species including woody and herbaceous species grown in wet and warm subtropical regions were collected and classified into woody and herb functional groups. Net photosynthesis (P (n)) and dark respiration (R) were measured at constant 25A degrees C under neither water nor nitrogen limited condition to assess whether the R/P (n) ratio was constant across different species and functional groups. Our results suggest that P (n) and R were highly skewed among the 39 species, ranging from 5 to 25 and 1 to 5 mu mol m(-2) s(-1), respectively, while R/P (n) ratio was normally distributed at 0.1-0.3. Mean R/P (n) ratio was 0.19 for 39 species, and 0.20 and 0.18 for woody and herbs, respectively, showing no significant difference between the two groups. Leaf P (n), R, and R/P (n) ratios exhibited large variations across 39 species while R/P (n) ratio in our subtropical species was considerably higher than other studies. Our results also indicated that the difference within each group was even larger than between the two groups. Based on the pooled data set at global scale, and considering R/P (n) ratios performance under a combination of wet and warm conditions, the mean R/P (n) ratio of 0.19 fell between the R/P (n) ratio of 0.23 under dry and warm conditions and the R/P (n) ratio of 0.07 under cold regardless of the precipitation conditions. The comparison with published data sets indicated significant effects of long-term precipitation and temperature on leaf R/P (n) ratios at global scale, and we found that the plants adapting to warm and wet climates including our thirty-nine species tend to have a lower R/P (n) ratio.									6	0	5	0	6	0931-1890		WOS:000288393700014		J	Niklas, KJ; Cobb, ED								N, P, and C stoichiometry of Eranthis hyemalis (Ranunculaceae) and the allometry of plant growth								AMERICAN JOURNAL OF BOTANY				92	8			1256	1263		10.3732/ajb.92.8.1256			AUG 2005	2005	We report the nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P), and carbon (C) stoichiometry for each of the five organ-types (leaves, aerial stems, reproductive organs, roots, and tubers) of 17 actively growing Eranthis hyemalis plants differing in size (as measured in g C). We also report the N, P, and C stoichiometry of 20 winterized tubers, which are the only perennial organs of this species. Comparisons between whole-plant and winterized N/C and P/C levels indicate that N was resorbed from aerial organs and stored in tubers by the end of the growing season. Leaves were substantial reservoirs for N and P. With few exceptions, N scaled isometrically with respect to C for each organ-type, whereas P scaled as the 3/4 power of C. Thus, N is proportional to P-3/4 which is proportional to C regardless of organ-type. Additionally, annual growth rate G of shoots (leaves and aerial stems) scaled as the -3 power of leaf N/P quotients such that G was proportional to the 3/4 power of leaf P. We suggest that these scaling relationships (together with previously reported allometric trends across herbaceous species) show that growth is constrained by organ-specific N and P allocation patterns (presumably to proteins and ribosomes. respectively).									11	5	10	1	17	0002-9122		WOS:000230882500005	21646146	J	Moles, AT; Westoby, M								Seed mass and seedling establishment after fire in Ku-ring-gai Chase National Park, Sydney, Australia								AUSTRAL ECOLOGY				29	4			383	390		10.1111/j.1442-9993.2004.01374.x			AUG 2004	2004	Relationships between seed mass and several aspects of plant regeneration ecology were investigated in a post-fire environment in Ku-ring-gai Chase National Park near Sydney, Australia. We found a significant positive relationship between seed mass and time to seedling emergence (P < 0.001) and a strong negative relationship between seed mass and time between emergence and production of the first true leaf (P < 0.001). Surprisingly, we found no relationship between seed mass and seedling establishment (P = 0.21). It seems most likely that this lack of relationship is a result of the many stochastic factors affecting seedling establishment during any given recruitment episode at any given site. A cause of mortality was assigned to 56% of the 781 seedlings that died during the present study. There was no relationship between cause of death and seed mass (P = 0.28). Of the seedlings for which the cause of death was known, 57% were killed by herbivory and 21% were killed by drought. Seedling-seedling competition affected only one species.									10	3	14	0	17	1442-9985		WOS:000223057500003		J	Temperton, VM; Grayston, SJ; Jackson, G; Barton, CVM; Millard, P; Jarvis, PG				Barton, Craig/B-7026-2008; Millard, Peter /F-1048-2011				Effects of elevated carbon dioxide concentration on growth and nitrogen fixation in Alnus glutinosa in a long-term field experiment								TREE PHYSIOLOGY				23	15			1051	1059					OCT 2003	2003	Nitrogen-fixing plant species may respond more positively to elevated atmospheric carbon dioxide concentrations ([CO,]) than other species because of their ability to maintain a high internal nutrient supply. A key factor in the growth response of trees to elevated [CO2] is the availability of nitrogen, although how elevated [CO2] influences the rate of N-2-fixation of nodulated trees growing under field conditions is unclear. To elucidate this relationship, we measured total biomass, relative growth rate, net assimilation rate (NAR), leaf area and net photosynthetic rate of N-2-fixing Alnus glutinosa (L.) Gaertn. (common alder) trees grown for 3 years in open-top chambers in the presence of either ambient or elevated atmospheric [CO2] and two soil N regimes: full nutrient solution or no fertilizer. Nitrogen fixation by Frankia spp. in the root nodules of unfertilized trees was assessed by the acetylene reduction method. We hypothesized that unfertilized trees would show similar positive growth and physiological responses to elevated [CO2] as the fertilized trees.Growth in elevated [CO2] stimulated (relative) net photosynthesis and (absolute) total biomass accumulation. Relative total biomass increased, and leaf nitrogen remained stable, only during the first year of the experiment. Toward the end of the experiment, signs of photosynthetic acclimation occurred, i.e., down-regulation of the photosynthetic apparatus. Relative growth rate was not significantly affected by elevated [CO2] because although NAR was increased, the effect on relative growth rate was negated by a reduction in leaf area ratio. Neither leaf area nor leaf P concentration was affected by growth in elevated [CO2].Nodule mass increased on roots of unfertilized trees exposed to elevated [CO2] compared with fertilized trees exposed to ambient [CO2]. There was also a biologically significant, although not statistically significant, stimulation of nitrogenase activity in nodules exposed to elevated [CO2]. Root nodules of trees exposed to elevated [CO2] were smaller and more evenly spaced than root nodules of trees exposed and [CO2] effects on growth, biomass and photosynthesis indicates that the unfertilized trees maintained similar CO2-induced growth and photosynthetic enhancements as the fertilized trees. This implies that alder trees growing in natural conditions, which are often limited by soil N availability, should nevertheless benefit from increasing atmospheric [CO2].									19	0	18	0	20	0829-318X		WOS:000186057000005	12975129	J	Moriana, A; Fereres, E								Plant indicators for scheduling irrigation of young olive trees								IRRIGATION SCIENCE				21	2			83	90		10.1007/s00271-001-0053-8			MAR 2002	2002	The sensitivity of several water status indicators was determined in irrigated young olive trees subjected to two drought periods at Cordoba, Spain. Trunk diameter fluctuations (TDF) were monitored continuously and stem water potential (psi), leaf photosynthesis (P-n) and conductance (g(1)) were measured periodically on trees where irrigation was interrupted or which were fully irrigated. During the first period of water deprivation in late spring, only some of the TDF-derived parameters were able to detect significant differences caused by water deficits, while there were no differences in stem psi, P-n and g(1). All water stress indicators responded during the second drought period in midsummer. However, differences in maximum trunk diameter were detected several days before significant stem psi differences of about 0.2 MPa were established between treatments. Stem psi differences declined further to 0.6 MPa before differences in leaf P-n and g(1) became significant. Of all TDF-derived indices, trunk growth rate was the most sensitive to water deficits while treatment differences in maximum daily shrinkage were insignificant in the young trees. It is concluded that continuous monitoring of trunk diameter provides the most sensitive indicator for accurate, automated irrigation scheduling of young olive trees under intensive production.									78	4	59	2	84	0342-7188		WOS:000174995700005		J	Graham, JH; Eissenstat, DM				Graham, James/B-7049-2008				Field evidence for the carbon cost of citrus mycorrhizas								NEW PHYTOLOGIST				140	1			103	110		10.1046/j.1469-8137.1998.00251.x			SEP 1998	1998	Mycorrhizas can produce negative crop responses when phosphorus availability is sufficient in agricultural soils because the fungi are of no benefit in nutrient acquisition yet continue to colonize roots and invoke parasitic costs. Benomyl fungicide was used to test this prediction in the field by limiting mycorrhizal colonization of 2-yr-old Valencia orange trees (Citrus sinensis (L.) Osbeck) on four rootstocks of varying mycorrhizal dependency in P-deficient soil fertilized with and without phosphate. No known fungal pathogens of citrus roots controlled by benomyl were present on the trees or in the field soil. Young trees with or without P fertilization and benomyl treatment remained sufficient in P (greater than or equal to 0.10% leaf P) throughout the 27-month study. Root zone drenches of benomyl reduced mycorrhizal colonization and leaf P status of Valencia orange trees on the three slower-growing rootstocks, trifoliate orange (Poncirus trifoliata (L.) Raf.), Swingle citrumelo (Citrus paradisi Macf. x P. trifoliata) and sour orange (Citrus aurantium L.), for the duration of three growing seasons. Benomyl affected root colonization and P status of trees on the faster-growing rootstock, Volkamer lemon (Citrus volkameriana Tan. and Pasq.), less than for trees on the slower-growing rootstocks and the effects were sustained for only two seasons. The shorter duration of benomyl effect for trees on Volkamer lemon rootstock compared with the slower-growing rootstocks was explained by the loss of inhibition of mycorrhizal activity when roots grew out of the drench zone and mycorrhizas were no longer in direct contact with the fungicide. Benomyl treatment increased growth rate of Valencia orange on the slow-growing rootstocks from 5 to 17 % after three seasons, and from 2 to 9 % on Volkamer lemon rootstock after two seasons compared with the non-benomyl treated trees. The benomyl effect was attributed to reduction of costs of root colonization over time, and consequently, a greater availability of carbon assimilate for shoot growth of trees. Since mycorrhizal fungi are ubiquitous in fertilized agricultural soils and obligate biotrophs on the roots of most crop species, these results indicate a need to further investigate whether negative growth responses of P-sufficient plants in the field occur because mycorrhizal fungi are no longer behaving as mutualists.									59	0	58	1	61	0028-646X		WOS:000076565000011		J	STINCHCOMBE, GR; STOTT, KG								A COMPARISON OF HERBICIDE-CONTROLLED ORCHARD GROUND COVER MANAGEMENT-SYSTEMS ON THE VIGOR AND YIELD OF APPLES								JOURNAL OF HORTICULTURAL SCIENCE				58	4			477	489					1983	1983										2	0	1	0	2	0022-1589		WOS:A1983RV52400004		J	SERR, EUGENE F.								Response of Persian walnut to superphosphate								PROC AMER SOC HORT SCI				77				301	307					1961	1961	Triple superphosphate soil applications caused improvement in growth rate, foliage condition and crop production in Persian walnuts growing on volcanic soils of Lake County. Low leaf P and Ca content were correlated with poor tree condition before treatment. Levels of both increased following treatment. Improvement has endured for 5 years. || ABSTRACT AUTHORS: Author									1	0	1	0	1			BCI:BCI19613600077882		